[{"question":"How many countries border San Marino?","correctAnswer":1,"answer2":2,"answer3":3,"answer4":4,"topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"With how many countries does the US share a land border?","correctAnswer":2,"answer2":3,"answer3":4,"answer4":1,"topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"How many faces has the clock on Big Ben's tower?","correctAnswer":4,"answer2":2,"answer3":3,"answer4":1,"topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"How many hours behind Greenwich Mean Time is California?","correctAnswer":8,"answer2":6,"answer3":10,"answer4":12,"topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"How many fountains are found in the gardens at the Palace of Versailles? ","correctAnswer":1400.0,"answer2":"140 ","answer3":14,"answer4":14000.0,"topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"How many candles were used to light the Hall of Mirrors in the Palace of Versailles?    ","correctAnswer":3000.0,"answer2":300,"answer3":33000.0,"answer4":333000.0,"topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"On a clear day how far can one see from the observation platform of the Empire State Building?","correctAnswer":"130 km","answer2":"3 km","answer3":"30 km","answer4":"630  km","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"Peter Minuit of the Dutch West India Company bought Manhattan island from the local indians in 1626 with cloth, trinkets and beads worth the equivalent  of what?","correctAnswer":"24 dollars","answer2":"24 cents","answer3":"240 dollars","answer4":"2,400 dollars","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"In which European city is Schiphol airport?","correctAnswer":"Amsterdam","answer2":"Budapest","answer3":"Warsaw","answer4":"Athens","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"Where is Dam Square?","correctAnswer":"Amsterdam","answer2":"Berlin","answer3":"Copenhagen","answer4":"Darmstadt","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"In which city can one visit the Palace of the Popes?","correctAnswer":"Avignon","answer2":"Rome","answer3":"Nancy","answer4":"Madrid","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"The jade green waters of Lake Louise are found in which national park?","correctAnswer":"Banff, Canada","answer2":"Kruger, South Africa","answer3":"Serengeti, Tanzania","answer4":"Yellowstone, USA","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"In which county can one find Luton Airport?","correctAnswer":"Bedfordshire","answer2":"Hertfordshire","answer3":"Kent","answer4":"Essex","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"With 196 tonnes, the heaviest what ever built is found within the walls of the Kremlin?","correctAnswer":"bell","answer2":"gold bar","answer3":"cannon ball","answer4":"statue","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"Since 1981, Mumbai is the official name for which Indian city?","correctAnswer":"Bombay","answer2":"Calcutta","answer3":"Delhi","answer4":"Bangalore","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"The name of which capital city is the Latin word for a red dye wood?","correctAnswer":"Brasilia","answer2":"Vienna","answer3":"Berlin","answer4":"Rome","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"Where in London can one view the Magna Carta and the Rosetta Stone?","correctAnswer":"British Museum","answer2":"Tate Gallery","answer3":"National Gallery","answer4":"Tower of London","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"With 40 tonnes, the largest what ever built is found within the walls of the Kremlin?","correctAnswer":"cannon","answer2":"crucifix","answer3":"chandelier","answer4":"chalice","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"Where is the Astronaut Hall of Fame located?","correctAnswer":"Cape Canaveral","answer2":"Washington","answer3":"Houston","answer4":"New York","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"In which city can one board the luxurious 'Blue Train'?","correctAnswer":"Cape Town","answer2":"Edinburgh","answer3":"Vancouver","answer4":"Istanbul","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"In which city does the National Assembly of Wales sit?","correctAnswer":"Cardiff","answer2":"Newport","answer3":"Swansea","answer4":"St. Davids","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which London street does one associate with the 1960s fashion scene?","correctAnswer":"Carnaby","answer2":"Fleet","answer3":"Threadneedle","answer4":"Pall Mall","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"In which city is the world famous Sears Tower skyscraper located?","correctAnswer":"Chicago","answer2":"New York","answer3":"Boston","answer4":"Detroit","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"How many litres of beer are consumed each year at the Oktoberfest in Munich?","correctAnswer":"circa 6,000,000","answer2":" circa 60,000,000","answer3":"circa 600,000","answer4":"circa 60,000","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which metal was used to construct the outside hull of the Statue of Liberty?","correctAnswer":"copper","answer2":"brass","answer3":"silver","answer4":"iron","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"In which city is the world famous Burg Al Arab skyscraper located?","correctAnswer":"Dubai","answer2":"Cairo","answer3":"Tehran","answer4":"Kuwait City","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which language is Afrikaans derived from?","correctAnswer":"Dutch","answer2":"German","answer3":"Spanish","answer4":"English","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"The Royal Mile is a famous street in which capital city?","correctAnswer":"Edinburgh","answer2":"Ottawa","answer3":"London","answer4":"Dublin","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which European capital has the nickname 'The Athens of the north'?","correctAnswer":"Edinburgh","answer2":"Paris","answer3":"Berlin","answer4":"Helsinki","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"Famine in which country triggered the Band Aid Charity?","correctAnswer":"Ethiopia","answer2":"Sudan","answer3":"South Africa","answer4":"Zimbabwe","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which country's postage stamps bear the inscription \"Suomi\"?","correctAnswer":"Finland","answer2":"Sweden","answer3":"Denmark","answer4":"Norway","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"The Uffizien museum, a feast for the eyes for lovers of Renaissance paintings, is located in which city?","correctAnswer":"Florence","answer2":"Rome","answer3":"Vatican City","answer4":"Milan","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"Whose upper house of Parliament is called the Bundesrat?","correctAnswer":"Germany's","answer2":"Belgium's","answer3":"France's","answer4":"Spain's","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"What is the name of the film prize awarded each year at the Venice film festival?","correctAnswer":"Golden Lion","answer2":"Golden Bear","answer3":"Golden Eagle","answer4":"Golden Star","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"In which country is the harbour city Mumbai?","correctAnswer":"India","answer2":"China","answer3":"Senegal","answer4":"Japan","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"In which city is the world famous skyscraper Petronas Towers located?","correctAnswer":"Kuala Lumpur","answer2":"Shanghai","answer3":"New York","answer4":"Dubai","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"It is said that the residents of which European capital never sleep?","correctAnswer":"Madrid","answer2":"Oslo","answer3":"Warsaw","answer4":"Dublin","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"In which city is the famous Prado museum?","correctAnswer":"Madrid","answer2":"St Petersburg","answer3":"Florence","answer4":"Vatican","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which destination for 60s hippies has been called the Paris of the Sahara?  ","correctAnswer":"Marrakesh","answer2":"Tripolis","answer3":"Cairo","answer4":"Luxor","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"The German city of Lübeck is world famous for which product?","correctAnswer":"marzipan","answer2":"pickled herring","answer3":"sauerkraut","answer4":"Frankfurters","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"GUM is the world famous dept store in which city?","correctAnswer":"Moscow","answer2":"New York","answer3":"Paris","answer4":"Tokyo","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which famous castle was the inspiration for the Disney theme park castle?","correctAnswer":"Neuschwanstein Castle","answer2":"Edinburgh Castle","answer3":"Windsor Castle","answer4":"Mount Saint Michel Castle","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"In which city is the world famous Chrysler Building skyscraper located?","correctAnswer":"New York","answer2":"Chicago","answer3":"San Francisco ","answer4":"Detroit","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"In which city is the world famous Woolworth Building skyscraper located?","correctAnswer":"New York","answer2":"London","answer3":"Chicago","answer4":"Boston","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"In which country can one find the Giant's Causeway?","correctAnswer":"Northern Ireland","answer2":"Scotland","answer3":"France","answer4":"Canada","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"The famous 'Lake Palace' in India, once a summer residence for royalty and now a luxury hotel, was the setting  for which action film? ","correctAnswer":"Octopussy","answer2":"Star Wars. The Empire Strikes Back","answer3":"Mission Impossible II","answer4":"Crouching Tiger, Hidden Dragon","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"In which capital city is the Roland Garos stadium?","correctAnswer":"Paris","answer2":"Prague","answer3":"Madrid","answer4":"Budapest","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"The victory goddess Victoria and her chariot on the top of the Brandenburger Gate in Berlin spent the years between 1806 and 1814 in which capital city?","correctAnswer":"Paris","answer2":"London","answer3":"Moscow","answer4":"Rome","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"The Emperors Palace or Forbidden City is located in which city?","correctAnswer":"Peking","answer2":"Shanghai","answer3":"Hong Kong","answer4":"Xi'an","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"The Cathedral of our Lady in Antwerp contains four masterpieces depicting Biblical scenes by which famous Baroque painter?","correctAnswer":"Peter Paul Rubens","answer2":"Vincent van Gogh","answer3":"Raffael","answer4":"Rembrandt","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"The 'Liberty Bell' is found in which US city?","correctAnswer":"Philadelphia","answer2":"Washington","answer3":"New York","answer4":"Boston","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"In which harbour city is Lord Nelson's flagship HMS Victory?","correctAnswer":"Portsmouth","answer2":"Plymouth","answer3":"Bristol","answer4":"Liverpool","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"The longest bridge built in the middleages in Europe, the Charles Bridge, is located in which capital city?","correctAnswer":"Prague","answer2":"London","answer3":"Paris","answer4":"Oslo","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"What creature appears on the Welsh national flag?","correctAnswer":"Red dragon","answer2":"Yellow dafffodil","answer3":"Green leek","answer4":"White sheep","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which city has the nickname 'Venice of the north'?","correctAnswer":"St Petersburg","answer2":"Montreal","answer3":"Glasgow","answer4":"Helsinki","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which famous city, sometimes called the Venice of the north, was built on 12 islands?","correctAnswer":"St Petersburg","answer2":"Glasgow","answer3":"Ottawa","answer4":"Oslo","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"What is the name of the famous mountain that overlooks Cape Town, South Africa?","correctAnswer":"Table","answer2":"Plate","answer3":"Chalice","answer4":"Divan","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"In which famous buiding did Catherine the Great keep her private art collection?","correctAnswer":"The Eremitage","answer2":"The Kremlin","answer3":"The Summer Palace","answer4":"The Bolshoi Theatre","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"Niagara Falls Canada, where the awe inspiring Horseshoe Falls is located, has been given which nickname?    ","correctAnswer":"The Honeymoon City","answer2":"The Misty City","answer3":"The Windy City","answer4":"The City of Lights","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which golf course is called 'the home of golf'?","correctAnswer":"The Royal and Ancient Golf Club St Andrews","answer2":"Gleneagles","answer3":"Pebble Beach","answer4":"Sunningdale","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"Hadrian's Wall was built in order to keep which wild men out of the Roman Empire?","correctAnswer":"The Scots","answer2":"The Welsh","answer3":"The Vikings","answer4":"The Mongols","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"The Potala Palace was once the winter residence for which man? ","correctAnswer":"The Dalai Lama","answer2":"Pu  Li","answer3":"Kubla Khan","answer4":"El Cid","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"In which city is the CN Tower, the tallest free standing structure in the world?","correctAnswer":"Toronto","answer2":"Chicago","answer3":"Hong Kong","answer4":"Moscow","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"The 'Book of Kells', a 1,300 year old masterpiece of western calligraphy, is found in which university?","correctAnswer":"Trinity College, Dublin","answer2":" Oxford","answer3":"Cambridge","answer4":"Sorbonne, Paris  ","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"Angel Falls, the worlds highest waterfall is located in which country?","correctAnswer":"Venezuela","answer2":"Zambia","answer3":"Canada","answer4":"Switzerland","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":" In which city is the famous Bridge of Sighs?","correctAnswer":"Venice","answer2":"Paris","answer3":"Rome","answer4":"Prague","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which Canadian provincial capital is nicknamed 'Little England'?","correctAnswer":"Victoria","answer2":"Toronto","answer3":"Quebec City","answer4":"Halifax","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"The Taj Mahal was constructed with which material?","correctAnswer":"White Marble","answer2":"White Granite","answer3":"White Ivory","answer4":"White Opals","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"In which US national park is the geysir named 'Old Faithful' located?","correctAnswer":"Yellowstone","answer2":"Banff","answer3":"Grand Teton","answer4":"Bryce Canyon","topic":"geography","difficulty":1},{"question":"How many bridges are there over the firth of fourth?","correctAnswer":2,"answer2":3,"answer3":4,"answer4":1,"topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many American states begin and end with the letter 'A'?","correctAnswer":3,"answer2":4,"answer3":5,"answer4":2,"topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many time zones are there in the USA?","correctAnswer":4,"answer2":5,"answer3":2,"answer4":1,"topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"What is the unlucky number in China?","correctAnswer":4,"answer2":13,"answer3":7,"answer4":33,"topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many stories high is the Empire State building?","correctAnswer":102,"answer2":62,"answer3":162,"answer4":202,"topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"What is the population of the Czech Rep?","correctAnswer":"10.3 million","answer2":"4.5 million","answer3":"57.6 million","answer4":"80.2 million","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Angel Falls, the highest waterfall in the world is how many times higher than the Niagara Falls?","correctAnswer":"15X","answer2":"5X","answer3":"2X","answer4":"25X","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"How much does the Petersglocke, the worlds heaviest church bell in the Cologne Cathedral weigh ?","correctAnswer":"24 tonnes","answer2":"4 tonnes","answer3":"240 tonnes","answer4":"124 tonnes","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"To the nearest million, what was the population of Wales in 2001?","correctAnswer":"3 million","answer2":"1 million","answer3":"5 million","answer4":"10 million","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"What is the cozy interior temperature in the world famous Ice Hotel in Jukkasjärvi Sweden?","correctAnswer":"-5° C to -8°C","answer2":"-13°C to -16°C","answer3":"0°C to -3°C","answer4":"-27°C to -30°C","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"What is the population of Iran?","correctAnswer":"71.4 million","answer2":"3.8 million","answer3":"33.5 million","answer4":"144.5 million","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"What is the population of Vietnam?","correctAnswer":"78.8 million","answer2":"10.1 million","answer3":"39.9 million","answer4":"123.3 million","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Lake Assal is the lowest point on which continent?","correctAnswer":"Africa","answer2":"Asia","answer3":"Australia","answer4":"Antarctic","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Where do the largest vegetables in the US grow?","correctAnswer":"Alaska","answer2":"Hawaii","answer3":"Florida","answer4":"New Mexico","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"What is the name of the famous ancient temple city in the jungle of Cambodia?","correctAnswer":"Angkor Wat","answer2":"Penang","answer3":"Amanwana","answer4":"Yogyakarta","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"The Chrysler Building in New York City is an example of which style of architecture?","correctAnswer":"Art Deco","answer2":"Byzantine","answer3":"Post Modernism","answer4":"Baroque","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"The Sagrada Familia Cathedral in Barcelona is an example of which style of architecture?","correctAnswer":"Art Nouveau","answer2":"Neo Gothic","answer3":"Renaissance","answer4":"Romanesque","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Lake Eyre is the lowest point on which continent?","correctAnswer":"Australia","answer2":"Europe","answer3":"North America","answer4":"Antarctic","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"The Gibson desert is found in which country?","correctAnswer":"Australia","answer2":"South Africa","answer3":"Canada","answer4":"USA","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which country does not border Poland?","correctAnswer":"Austria","answer2":"Slovakia","answer3":"Germany","answer4":"Lithuania","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"The Palace of Versailles is an example of which style of architecture?","correctAnswer":"Baroque","answer2":"Romanesque","answer3":"Greek","answer4":"Gothic","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"St Paul's Cathedral in London is an example of which style of architecture?","correctAnswer":"Baroque","answer2":"Art Deco","answer3":"Gothic","answer4":"Neo Classical","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"What is the only breed of dog that is allowed to testify in a US courtroom?","correctAnswer":"Bloodhound","answer2":"Poodle","answer3":"German Shepard","answer4":"Collie","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Until 1763, Salvador de Bahia was the capital of which country?","correctAnswer":"Brazil","answer2":"Spain","answer3":"Mexico","answer4":"Portugal","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"The Hagia Sophia in Istanbul is an example of which style of architecture?","correctAnswer":"Byzantine","answer2":"Roman","answer3":"Gothic","answer4":"Greek","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"The Bay of Fundy is off the coast of which country?","correctAnswer":"Canada","answer2":"Australia","answer3":"New Zealand","answer4":"South Africa","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"The name of which capital city stems from the native word for 'meeting place'?","correctAnswer":"Canberra, Australia","answer2":"Paris, France","answer3":"Ottawa, Canada","answer4":"Edinburgh, Scotland","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"What is the name of the 13th century spa city in the Czech Rep. that attracted the likes of Chopin, Beethoven, Bach and King Edward VII?","correctAnswer":"Carlsbad","answer2":"Spa","answer3":"Baden Baden","answer4":"Bad Gastein","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which country has only one time zone?","correctAnswer":"China","answer2":"Canada","answer3":"Russia","answer4":"Brazil","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which country has the largest army in the world?","correctAnswer":"China","answer2":"North Korea","answer3":"India","answer4":"USA","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which contemporary artist wrapped up the Reichstag in Berlin with 100,000 m2 of polypropylene fabric in the summer of 1995?","correctAnswer":"Christo","answer2":"Yoko Ono","answer3":"H.R. Giger","answer4":"Andy Warhol","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"When did the construction of the  Pyramids of Giseh first begin?  ","correctAnswer":"circa 2500 BC","answer2":" circa 5500 BC","answer3":"circa 500 BC","answer4":"circa 50 BC","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"The Grand Place or main market square in Brussels hosts the 'flower carpet' festival each August. How many begonias are used?","correctAnswer":"circa 700,000","answer2":"circa 7,000,000","answer3":"circa 70,000","answer4":"circa 7,000","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which cathedral is the Petersglocke, the worlds largest church bell?","correctAnswer":"Cologne","answer2":"St Peters, Vatican City","answer3":"Canterbury","answer4":"Durham","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which country does not border Bolivia?","correctAnswer":"Colombia","answer2":"Brazil","answer3":"Peru","answer4":"Chile","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which country does not border Greece?","correctAnswer":"Croatia","answer2":"Turkey","answer3":"Albania","answer4":"Bulgaria","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Banana is a harbour city in which country?","correctAnswer":"Dem Rep of Congo","answer2":"Brazil","answer3":"Indonesia","answer4":"Colombia","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Mount Elbrus is the highest point on which continent?","correctAnswer":"Europe","answer2":"Asia","answer3":"North America","answer4":"Antarctic","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"The world famous Oberammergau passion play in Bayern is held how often?","correctAnswer":"every 10 years","answer2":"every year","answer3":"every 50 years","answer4":"every 2 years","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which city, famous for its ship building, was the ocean liner QE2  built?","correctAnswer":"Glasgow","answer2":"Belfast","answer3":"Southampton","answer4":"Portsmouth","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"South Africa is the world's leading exporter of what?","correctAnswer":"Gold","answer2":"Silver","answer3":"Diamond","answer4":"Platinum","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which railway station has the most platforms in the world?","correctAnswer":"Grand Central, New York","answer2":"Waterloo, London","answer3":"Frankfurt Main","answer4":"Gare du Nord, Paris","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which strait seperates the Persian gulf and the gulf of Oman?","correctAnswer":"Hormuz","answer2":"Bosporus","answer3":"Malacca","answer4":"Dardanelles","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"What country does not border Afghanistan?","correctAnswer":"India","answer2":"Pakistan","answer3":"China","answer4":"Uzbekistan","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Where would you find the volcano named Krakatoa? ","correctAnswer":"Indonesia","answer2":"Malaysia","answer3":"China","answer4":"India","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Dingle Bay is off the coast of which country?","correctAnswer":"Ireland","answer2":"Canada","answer3":"Australia","answer4":"New Zealand","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which city in Turkey is located in Europe and in Asia?","correctAnswer":"Istanbul","answer2":"Ankara","answer3":"Dodomar","answer4":"Pamukulai","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Montego Bay is off the coast of which country?","correctAnswer":"Jamaica","answer2":"Barbados","answer3":"Bermuda","answer4":"Trinidad and Tobago","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Where in New York City is the 'Canyon of Heroes', where the famous ticker tape parades take place?","correctAnswer":"Lower Broadway","answer2":"Wall Street","answer3":"Fifth Avenue","answer4":"Times Square","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"According to the World Health Organisation which capital city has the worst air pollution?","correctAnswer":"Mexico City","answer2":"London","answer3":"Moscow","answer4":"Cairo","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Who designed the uniform worn by the Vatican City's Swiss Guard?","correctAnswer":"Michalangelo","answer2":"Da Vinci","answer3":"Raffael","answer4":"Galileo","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which Is The Most Densely Populated Country In Europe?","correctAnswer":"Monaco","answer2":"Vatican City","answer3":"Andorra","answer4":"Luxembourg","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"What do the citizens of Brussels love to eat with their frites (French fries)?","correctAnswer":"mussels","answer2":"savoury sausage","answer3":"eel","answer4":"Brussel sprouts","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"The Houses Of Parliament in London is an example of which style of architecture?","correctAnswer":"Neo Gothic","answer2":"Baroque","answer3":"Gothic","answer4":"Art Deco","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"The Dominion Parliament buildings in Ottawa are an example of which style of architecture?","correctAnswer":"Neo Gothic","answer2":"Roman","answer3":"Renaissance","answer4":"Art Deco","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which country is the mountain named Annapurna found?","correctAnswer":"Nepal","answer2":"Argentina","answer3":"Russia","answer4":"Switzerland","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which US state is Area 51?","correctAnswer":"Nevada","answer2":"New Mexico","answer3":"Texas","answer4":"Arizona","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"The Bay of Plenty is off the coast of which country?","correctAnswer":"New Zealand","answer2":"Australia","answer3":"Canada","answer4":"South Africa","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which country is Mt Cook?","correctAnswer":"New Zealand","answer2":"Canada","answer3":"USA","answer4":"Argentina","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Into which body of water does the Rhine river flow?","correctAnswer":"North Sea","answer2":"Black sea","answer3":"Caspian Sea","answer4":"Baltic Sea","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which country is there a town named 'Hell'?","correctAnswer":"Norway","answer2":"Canada","answer3":"Australia","answer4":"Ireland","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"On what river is the capital city of Canada?","correctAnswer":"Ottawa","answer2":"Windigo","answer3":"Winnipeg ","answer4":"Montreal ","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"The mysterious Inca city Machu Picchu is found in which country?","correctAnswer":"Peru","answer2":"Mexico","answer3":"Chile","answer4":"Colombia","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which country does not border Austria?","correctAnswer":"Poland","answer2":"Germany","answer3":"Hungary","answer4":"Czech Rep","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"With a capacity for 220,000 spectators, in which capital city is Strahov, the largest stadium in the world?","correctAnswer":"Prague","answer2":" Moscow","answer3":"Warsaw","answer4":"Vienna","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which City would you find St. Peter's Basilica?","correctAnswer":"Rome","answer2":"Madrid","answer3":"St. Petersburg","answer4":"Moscow","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Why was the Munich Oktoberfest cancelled in 1923 and 1924?","correctAnswer":"Runaway inflation","answer2":"Civil war","answer3":"Spanish flu","answer4":"Brewery strike","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"When motoring west in which city does Route 66 end?","correctAnswer":"Santa Monica","answer2":"LA","answer3":"Oakland","answer4":"San Francisco","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which city is the world famous Jin Mao skyscraper located?","correctAnswer":"Shanghai","answer2":"Hong Kong","answer3":"Beijing","answer4":"Taipei","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which metal made the Bolivian city Potosi one of the richest cities in the world in the 17th century?","correctAnswer":"silver","answer2":"gold","answer3":"aluminium","answer4":"copper","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which country produces the most gold?","correctAnswer":"South Africa","answer2":"Australia","answer3":"Dem Rep Congo","answer4":"Canada","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"The Valdes Peninsula is the lowest point on which continent?","correctAnswer":"South America","answer2":"Europe","answer3":"Antarctic","answer4":"Australia","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Mount Aconcagua is the highest point on which continent?","correctAnswer":"South America","answer2":"Asia","answer3":"Antarctic","answer4":"Australia","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which country is the harbour city Inchon?","correctAnswer":"South Korea","answer2":"India","answer3":"Brazil","answer4":"Japan","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"50% of all the men on the Greek island Corfu have which first name?","correctAnswer":"Spiro","answer2":"Achilles","answer3":"Alexis","answer4":"Stavros","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"What is the name of the largest star sapphire in the world which is found in New York City's American Museum of Natural History?","correctAnswer":"Star of India","answer2":"Star of Africa ","answer3":"Star of Cairo","answer4":"Star of Bethleham","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which country does not border Luxembourg?","correctAnswer":"Switzerland","answer2":"Germany","answer3":"France","answer4":"Belgium","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which country is the mountain named Jungfrau found?","correctAnswer":"Switzerland","answer2":"Italy","answer3":"France","answer4":"New Zealand  ","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which country does not border South Africa?","correctAnswer":"Tanzania","answer2":"Namibia","answer3":"Swaziland","answer4":"Lesotho","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Younge Street, the longest street in the world, begins in which Canadian city?","correctAnswer":"Toronto","answer2":"Montreal","answer3":"Vancouver","answer4":"Quebec City","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"The ruins of ancient Carthage are found in the suburbs of which modern city?","correctAnswer":"Tunis","answer2":"Cairo","answer3":"Tripolis","answer4":"Beirut","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which African country is not a monarchy?","correctAnswer":"Tunisia","answer2":"Morocco","answer3":"Swaziland","answer4":"Lesotho","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which country is Mt Ararat?","correctAnswer":"Turkey","answer2":"Russia","answer3":"Nepal","answer4":"Switzerland","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which country does not border Turkey?","correctAnswer":"Turkmenistan","answer2":"Bulgaria","answer3":"Iran","answer4":"Iraq","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Where does a Halbardier Gaurdsman work?","correctAnswer":"Vatican","answer2":"Tower of London","answer3":"Mt Olympus","answer4":"Swiss Border","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"The oldest film festival in the world takes place in which European city?","correctAnswer":"Venice","answer2":"Cannes","answer3":"Berlin","answer4":"Edinburgh","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which goddess of victory is riding a chariot on the Brandenberger Gate in Berlin?","correctAnswer":"Victoria","answer2":"Athena","answer3":"Nike","answer4":"Brunhilda","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"What is Europe's longest river? ","correctAnswer":"Volga","answer2":"Danube","answer3":"Rhine","answer4":"Rhone","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which countries name stems from the Germanic word for foreign?","correctAnswer":"Wales","answer2":"Spain","answer3":"Germany","answer4":"Poland","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"With 1,000 plus rooms, what is the largest inhabited castle in the world?","correctAnswer":"Windsor Castle","answer2":"The Alhambra","answer3":"Warwich Castle","answer4":"Edinburgh Castle","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"During a WWII air raid the firemen in Freiburg im Breisgau used what to put out the fire in the historic Kaufhaus after they ran out of water?","correctAnswer":"wine","answer2":"schnapps","answer3":"beer","answer4":"milk","topic":"geography","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many months does the average American spend in a lifetime waiting at a red light?","correctAnswer":6,"answer2":1,"answer3":12,"answer4":18,"topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"How many countries lie between Mexico and Colombia?","correctAnswer":7,"answer2":10,"answer3":3,"answer4":5,"topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"How many hours a month does the average American spend in a shopping mall?","correctAnswer":12,"answer2":6,"answer3":24,"answer4":48,"topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"How many countries border Russia?","correctAnswer":14,"answer2":8,"answer3":25,"answer4":19,"topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"How many countries border China?","correctAnswer":16,"answer2":10,"answer3":26,"answer4":7,"topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"How many people live on Ellesmere Island, the 10th largest island in the world?","correctAnswer":106,"answer2":1106.0,"answer3":6,"answer4":10106.0,"topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"How many rooms are there in the White House?","correctAnswer":132,"answer2":32,"answer3":72,"answer4":272,"topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"How many lakes are there in Finland?","correctAnswer":187880.0,"answer2":8880.0,"answer3":87880.0,"answer4":887880.0,"topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"According to the UN how many people in the world are starving?","correctAnswer":820000000.0,"answer2":"1.5 billion","answer3":82000000.0,"answer4":420000000.0,"topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"Most sources claim that Route 66 is how many miles all the way?","correctAnswer":"2,448 miles","answer2":"2,848 miles","answer3":"1,848 miles","answer4":"3,448 miles","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"To the nearest thousand square kilometres what is the land area of Wales?","correctAnswer":"21,000 sq km","answer2":"5,000 sq km","answer3":"51,000 sq km","answer4":"100,100 sq km","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"What is the population of Saudi Arabia?","correctAnswer":"22.million","answer2":"123.3 million","answer3":"3.2 million","answer4":"65.2 million","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"The salt content in the Dead Sea which enables a swimmer to float like a cork is how many times higher than that of the Atlantic ocean?","correctAnswer":"7X","answer2":"2X","answer3":"22X","answer4":"77x","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"The Bridge of Sighs in Venice connected  the Doge's Palace with what?","correctAnswer":"A state prison and place of execution","answer2":"A tax office","answer3":"A hospital","answer4":"A Turkish bath house","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which European city is nicknamed the 'Granite City'?","correctAnswer":"Aberdeen","answer2":"The Vatican","answer3":"Lisbon","answer4":"Munich","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"The crown of the Empire State building was originally built for which purpose?","correctAnswer":"airship dock","answer2":"firemans lookout","answer3":"flag pole","answer4":"weather station","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"The Vinson Massive is the highest point on which continent?","correctAnswer":"Antarctic","answer2":"Europe","answer3":"Australia","answer4":"South America","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which country is the mountain named Aconcagua found?","correctAnswer":"Argentina","answer2":"Mexico","answer3":"Nepal","answer4":"Switzerland","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which country produces the most opals?","correctAnswer":"Australia","answer2":"India","answer3":"USA","answer4":"Russia","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"Mount Kosciusko is the highest point on which continent?","correctAnswer":"Australia","answer2":"Europe","answer3":"Antarctic","answer4":"Africa","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"Red, as in Red Square, was the old Slavic synonym for what?","correctAnswer":"beauty","answer2":"power","answer3":"wealth","answer4":"death","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"Into which body of water does the Danube river flow?","correctAnswer":"Black Sea","answer2":"North Sea","answer3":"Baltic Sea","answer4":"Caspian Sea","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which country does not have a bird on its flag?","correctAnswer":"Brazil","answer2":"Mexico","answer3":"Eygpt","answer4":"Dominican Rep","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which county is chequers, the prime ministers country residence?","correctAnswer":"Buckinghamshire","answer2":"Surrey","answer3":"Middlesex","answer4":"Oxfordshire","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"Lake Tahoe is on the border of Nevada and which other US state?","correctAnswer":"California","answer2":"Arizona","answer3":"Oregon","answer4":"Utah","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"The Gothic Chartes Cathedral in France has famous stained glass windows which produce which unique colour? ","correctAnswer":"Chartes Blue","answer2":"Chartes Green","answer3":"Chartes Red","answer4":"Chartes White","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which country is the port of Odense?","correctAnswer":"Denmark","answer2":"Sweden","answer3":"Norway","answer4":"Finland","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which country's name means Sunday?","correctAnswer":"Dominica","answer2":"Canada","answer3":"Russia","answer4":"Australia ","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"The highest mountain in Japan is Mount Fuji. What does Fuji mean? ","correctAnswer":"fire","answer2":"snow","answer3":"beauty","answer4":"harmony","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"The only person with 5 stars for excellence on the Hollywood Boulevard Walk Of Fame?","correctAnswer":"Gene Autry","answer2":"Diana Ross","answer3":"Bing Crosby","answer4":"George Burns","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which country does not border Slovakia?","correctAnswer":"Germany","answer2":"Hungary","answer3":"Austria","answer4":"Poland","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which country does the volcano Unzen grumble?","correctAnswer":"Japan","answer2":"Indonesia","answer3":"Philippines","answer4":"Iceland","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"Who was the Hollywood star who used his nose rather than hands or feet to make an impression in the sidewalk in front of 'Grauman's Chinese'?  ","correctAnswer":"Jimmy Durante","answer2":"Lassie","answer3":"Bob Hope","answer4":"Karl Malden","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which country does the volcano Mt Pelee grumble?","correctAnswer":"Martinique","answer2":"Iceland","answer3":"USA","answer4":"Italy","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which country produces the most silver?","correctAnswer":"Mexico","answer2":"Canada","answer3":"USA","answer4":"Brazil","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which country does the volcano Popocatepetl grumble?","correctAnswer":"Mexico","answer2":"Colombia","answer3":"Indonesia","answer4":"Greece","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which country does not border Libya?","correctAnswer":"Morocco","answer2":"Tunisia","answer3":"Algeria","answer4":"Eygpt","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"What is the most populated city north of the arctic circle?","correctAnswer":"Murmansk","answer2":"Ottawa","answer3":"Aberdeen","answer4":"Fairbanks","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which country does the volcano Ruapehu grumble?","correctAnswer":"New Zealand","answer2":"USA","answer3":"Indonesia","answer4":"Japan","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"According to the 'Global Peace Index' what is the safest country in the world?","correctAnswer":"Norway","answer2":"Canada","answer3":"Switzerland","answer4":"Australia","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"The Taj Mahal. Taj means 'crown', what does Mahal mean?","correctAnswer":"palace","answer2":"king","answer3":"queen","answer4":"crypt","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which street in London takes its name from a croquet like game once played by Charles I ?","correctAnswer":"Pall Mall","answer2":"Threadneedle","answer3":"Portobello","answer4":"Piccadilly","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which 'street' in London takes its name from the ornamental collars once made by the  17th century tailor Robert Baker?","correctAnswer":"Piccadilly","answer2":"Pall Mall","answer3":"Threadneedle","answer4":"Carnaby","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which country produces the most amber?","correctAnswer":"Poland","answer2":"Canada","answer3":"India","answer4":"China","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"The largest industrial complex in the world in the 19th century was found in which English harbour city?","correctAnswer":"Portsmouth","answer2":"Liverpool","answer3":"Newcastle","answer4":"Dover","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which country is not on the shores of Lake Victoria?","correctAnswer":"Rwanda","answer2":"Uganda","answer3":"Kenya","answer4":"Tanzania","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"The most visited city in Brittany has the highest ratio of sea food restaurants in Europe. Which port city is it?","correctAnswer":"Saint Malo","answer2":"Rennes","answer3":"Lannion","answer4":"Brest","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"A native indian legend claims that the scored marks that run down the side of Devil's Tower in Wyoming were gouged by a giant bear that was trying to reach what?","correctAnswer":"Seven stranded young maidens","answer2":"The honey coloured sun ","answer3":"His own shadow","answer4":"The other end of the rainbow","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"What are the winds called below the latitude 60 degrees south?","correctAnswer":"Shrieking 60s","answer2":"Screaming 60s","answer3":"Scary 60s","answer4":"Sullen 60s","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which Saint is not a US Virgin Island?","correctAnswer":"St Vincent","answer2":"St John","answer3":"St Croix","answer4":"St Thomas","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which country does not border Syria?","correctAnswer":"Sudan","answer2":"Isreal","answer3":"Lebanon","answer4":"Turkey","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which South American country would you find the city New Amsterdam?","correctAnswer":"Surinam","answer2":"Brazil","answer3":"Ecuador","answer4":"Guyana","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"What is found on the flag of Rwanda?","correctAnswer":"The letter 'R'","answer2":"A Star","answer3":"A Half Moon","answer4":"An Assualt Rifle","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which country does the volcano Kilauea grumble?","correctAnswer":"USA","answer2":"Japan","answer3":"Iceland","answer4":"Spain","topic":"geography","difficulty":3},{"question":"How many seats did the Spitfire fighter plane have?","correctAnswer":1,"answer2":2,"answer3":3,"answer4":"None","topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"How many wives did Henry VIII have?","correctAnswer":6,"answer2":5,"answer3":8,"answer4":4,"topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":" How many years did the '21 Year War'  between Sweden and Russia last? ","correctAnswer":21,"answer2":2,"answer3":55,"answer4":103,"topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"How many pennies were there in a pre decimal pound?","correctAnswer":240,"answer2":100,"answer3":200,"answer4":140,"topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"In which year was the Gunpowder Plot?","correctAnswer":1605,"answer2":1705,"answer3":1805,"answer4":1505,"topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"What year saw Adolph Hitler committing suicide?","correctAnswer":1945,"answer2":1944,"answer3":1946,"answer4":1947,"topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"In which year did JFK get assassinated?","correctAnswer":1963,"answer2":1966,"answer3":1968,"answer4":1960,"topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"In what year was the Falkland war?","correctAnswer":1982,"answer2":1984,"answer3":1980,"answer4":1978,"topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"In which year did a US-led coalition invade Iraq?","correctAnswer":2003,"answer2":2001,"answer3":2005,"answer4":1999,"topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which country did the USSR invade in 1979?","correctAnswer":"Afghanistan","answer2":"Iraq","answer3":"Iran","answer4":"China","topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"What was banned in USA in January 1920?","correctAnswer":"Alcohol","answer2":"Gambling","answer3":"Strikes","answer4":"Smoking","topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"One of the ancient world wonders, the 'Hanging Gardens', was found in which city?","correctAnswer":"Babylon","answer2":"Alexandria","answer3":"Rome","answer4":"Athens","topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"What was named after a hydrogen bomb test?","correctAnswer":"Bikini","answer2":"Hoola Hoop","answer3":"Frisbee","answer4":"Matchbox","topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"Robben Island was a prison near which city?","correctAnswer":"Cape Town","answer2":"San Francisco","answer3":"Athens","answer4":"Exeter","topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"Iceland and the Uk were caught up in which war?","correctAnswer":"Cod","answer2":"Herring","answer3":"Salmon","answer4":"Lobster","topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"King William the Bastard was also known by which other name?","correctAnswer":"Conqueror","answer2":"Rufus","answer3":"Orange","answer4":"Young King","topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"Of which country was Greenland a colony until 1981?","correctAnswer":"Denmark","answer2":"Sweden","answer3":"Russia","answer4":"Iceland","topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"The patron saint of England is famous for killing which type of creature?","correctAnswer":"Dragon","answer2":"Unicorn","answer3":"Angel","answer4":"Devil","topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"William Kemmler, back in 1890, was the first person to be killed using what lethal method?","correctAnswer":"Electric Chair","answer2":"Lethal Injection","answer3":"Death by Firing Squad","answer4":"Radiation","topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"What was special about Louise Brown, born July 25, 1978 in England?","correctAnswer":"First test tube baby","answer2":"First surrogate mother","answer3":"First surviving separated Siamese twin","answer4":"First surviving 20 week old foetus","topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"During the second world war in Germany it was forbidden to give a horse which name?","correctAnswer":"Hitler","answer2":"Stalin","answer3":"Mussolini","answer4":"Winston","topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"Who shot Lee Harvey Oswald?","correctAnswer":"Jack Ruby","answer2":"Jack Diamond","answer3":"Jack Emerald","answer4":"Jack Sapphire","topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"What was the first name of the US President known by the nickname JFK?","correctAnswer":"John","answer2":"Joe","answer3":"Jerry","answer4":"Jack","topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which explorer was the first to circumnavigate the globe?","correctAnswer":"Magellan","answer2":"Drake","answer3":"Marco Polo","answer4":"Columbus","topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"What species were Benjy and Laska, who were sent into space in 1958?","correctAnswer":"Mice","answer2":"Rats","answer3":"Monkeys","answer4":"Cats","topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which European country is ruled by The House of Orange?","correctAnswer":"Netherlands","answer2":"Belgium","answer3":"Sweden","answer4":"Norway","topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"What was the name of Christopher Columbus' smallest  ship?","correctAnswer":"Nina","answer2":"Tina","answer3":"Gina","answer4":"Mina","topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"What nationality was Roald Amundsen, the first man to reach the South Pole?","correctAnswer":"Norwegian","answer2":"Swedish","answer3":"Dutch","answer4":"Belgian","topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"In what industry did John Davidson Rockefeller get rich?","correctAnswer":"Oil","answer2":"Motor","answer3":"Music","answer4":"Movie","topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"Who was Pakistan's President in 2006?","correctAnswer":"Pervez Musharraf","answer2":"Pratibha Patil","answer3":"Nawaz Sharif","answer4":"Benazir Bhutto","topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which organisation was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 1917?","correctAnswer":"The Red Cross","answer2":"The Boy Scouts","answer3":"The Police","answer4":"Fathers for Justice","topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"What was 10th century English king Ethelred's nickname?","correctAnswer":"The Unready","answer2":"The Unlucky","answer3":"The Unshaven","answer4":"The Unsweetened","topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"Queen Elizabeth I of England was also known by which name?","correctAnswer":"The virgin queen","answer2":"The ginger queen","answer3":"The Richmond queen","answer4":"Bloody queen Elizabeth","topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"What weather phenomenon was the Norse god Thor thought to control? ","correctAnswer":"Thunder","answer2":"Lightening","answer3":"Typhoon","answer4":"Earthquakes","topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"King Henry VII of England was a member of which royal house?","correctAnswer":"Tudor","answer2":"York","answer3":"Lancaster","answer4":"Stuart","topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which Swedish motor vehicle manufacturer acquired the Dutch company DAF in the mid-1970s?","correctAnswer":"Volvo","answer2":"Saab","answer3":"Ford","answer4":"Dacia","topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"Where did Napoleon Bonaparte suffer his last defeat? ","correctAnswer":"Waterloo","answer2":"Rome","answer3":"Elba","answer4":"Leipzig","topic":"history","difficulty":1},{"question":"How many baths did Louis XIV take in his lifetime?","correctAnswer":3,"answer2":0,"answer3":51,"answer4":1,"topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many brothers and sisters did John F. Kennedy have?","correctAnswer":8,"answer2":3,"answer3":0,"answer4":2,"topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many days were there in one week in ancient Roman times?","correctAnswer":8,"answer2":7,"answer3":6,"answer4":10,"topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Out of every 10 women in Scotland, how many were pregnant on their wedding day, according to a Royal Commission of 1868?","correctAnswer":9,"answer2":5,"answer3":0,"answer4":2,"topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many kings of England have been named Edward? ","correctAnswer":9,"answer2":5,"answer3":4,"answer4":7,"topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many people are there in a US Grand Jury?","correctAnswer":23,"answer2":12,"answer3":11,"answer4":17,"topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"An estimated how many Popes have been murdered?","correctAnswer":26,"answer2":6,"answer3":13,"answer4":46,"topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many days was William Harrison President of the United States?","correctAnswer":32,"answer2":64,"answer3":16,"answer4":8,"topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many years were there between the Silver Jubilees of George V and Elizabeth II? ","correctAnswer":42,"answer2":32,"answer3":52,"answer4":62,"topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many km long was the Berlin Wall?","correctAnswer":42,"answer2":22,"answer3":82,"answer4":12,"topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"For how many years did Queen Victoria reign?","correctAnswer":63,"answer2":53,"answer3":43,"answer4":73,"topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"In Roman Numerals what does LXX stand for?","correctAnswer":70,"answer2":120,"answer3":60,"answer4":1200,"topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many pilgrims left Plymouth for America on the Mayflower?","correctAnswer":104,"answer2":202,"answer3":64,"answer4":264,"topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many years did the 'One Hundred Years War' last?","correctAnswer":114,"answer2":100,"answer3":99,"answer4":144,"topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many minutes did Neil Armstrong spend on the moon?","correctAnswer":152,"answer2":62,"answer3":1162.0,"answer4":12,"topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"According to Forbes new Rich List for 2009, how many billionares are there in the world? ","correctAnswer":793,"answer2":241,"answer3":2355.0,"answer4":5205.0,"topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which year did King Richard the 'lionhearted' die?","correctAnswer":1199,"answer2":99,"answer3":599,"answer4":1599,"topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which year did Henry VIII die?","correctAnswer":1547,"answer2":1597,"answer3":1647,"answer4":1507,"topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"What number on Pennsylvania Avenue would you find the white house?","correctAnswer":1600,"answer2":1200,"answer3":1800,"answer4":2000,"topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which year was St Pauls cathedral completed?","correctAnswer":1711,"answer2":1611,"answer3":1811,"answer4":1911,"topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which year was the revolver invented?","correctAnswer":1835,"answer2":1888,"answer3":1788,"answer4":1802,"topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"The Spanish Dublone was legal tender in the USA until which year?","correctAnswer":1857,"answer2":1777,"answer3":1657,"answer4":1927,"topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which year did electricity replace steam powered locomotives in the London Underground?","correctAnswer":1890,"answer2":1910,"answer3":1850,"answer4":1930,"topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which year was the Tower Bridge in London completed?","correctAnswer":1894,"answer2":1794,"answer3":1811,"answer4":1911,"topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"What year did the infamous San Francisco earthquake take place?","correctAnswer":1906,"answer2":1916,"answer3":1896,"answer4":1926,"topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which year was the first successful Channel crossing by an airplane?","correctAnswer":1909,"answer2":1903,"answer3":1913,"answer4":1897,"topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which year did the Titanic sink?","correctAnswer":1912,"answer2":1909,"answer3":1915,"answer4":1905,"topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which year was the infamous 'black sox' scandal?","correctAnswer":1919,"answer2":1909,"answer3":1929,"answer4":1939,"topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"In what year was Mahatma Gandhi assassinated?","correctAnswer":1948,"answer2":1950,"answer3":1942,"answer4":1938,"topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which year was the first successful heart transplant performed?","correctAnswer":1967,"answer2":1957,"answer3":1977,"answer4":1947,"topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which year was Prince Charles invested as The Prince of Wales?","correctAnswer":1969,"answer2":1979,"answer3":1959,"answer4":1989,"topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which year did the Rainbow Warrior sink?","correctAnswer":1985,"answer2":1986,"answer3":1987,"answer4":1984,"topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which year was Rajiv Gandhi assassinated?","correctAnswer":1991,"answer2":1981,"answer3":1971,"answer4":2001,"topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which year was the EURO TUNNEL officially opened?","correctAnswer":1994,"answer2":1990,"answer3":1998,"answer4":1986,"topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"What was the worlds population in AD 1?","correctAnswer":200000000.0,"answer2":500000000.0,"answer3":25000000.0,"answer4":"1 billion","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which amendment of the US constitution abolished slavery?","correctAnswer":"13th","answer2":"18th","answer3":"9th","answer4":"10th","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"For how long did Queen Jane rule England?","correctAnswer":"9 days","answer2":"9 years","answer3":"9 weeks","answer4":"9 months","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"According to an old legend, who can't shed more than 3 tears?","correctAnswer":"a witch","answer2":"a King","answer3":"a lawyer","answer4":"a bride ","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Who was the 2nd man in space?","correctAnswer":"Alan Shepard","answer2":"John Glenn","answer3":"Virgil Grissom","answer4":"Scott Carpenter","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"King Zog ruled which country?","correctAnswer":"Albania","answer2":"Russia","answer3":"Prussia","answer4":"Persia","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"What was the name of the research ship Charles Darwin travelled with?","correctAnswer":"Beagle","answer2":"Eagle","answer3":"Mermaid","answer4":"Turtle","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Charles Darwin was a passenger on which research ship?","correctAnswer":"Beagle","answer2":"Dolphin","answer3":"Eagle","answer4":"Albatross","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which city was the Titanic built?","correctAnswer":"Belfast","answer2":"Southampton","answer3":"Glasgow","answer4":"Liverpool","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Who was not the mayor of a US town?","correctAnswer":"Bruce Willis","answer2":"Sony Bono","answer3":"Anthony Hopkins","answer4":"Clint Eastwood","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which ship was the first to arrive and rescue Titanic survivors?","correctAnswer":"Carpathia","answer2":"Arizona","answer3":"George Washington","answer4":"Bremen","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which animal is not a Chinese year?","correctAnswer":"Cat","answer2":"Dragon","answer3":"Pig","answer4":"Rooster","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Who was the first wife of King Henry VIII?","correctAnswer":"Catherine of Aragon","answer2":"Anne Boleyn","answer3":"Jane Seymour","answer4":"Anne of Cleeves","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which English Monarch succeeded James I?","correctAnswer":"Charles I","answer2":"James II","answer3":"William III","answer4":"Mary II","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"The Gregorian Calendar was adopted by which country in 1912?","correctAnswer":"China","answer2":"Persia","answer3":"India","answer4":"Ireland","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which country was not a Portugese colony?","correctAnswer":"Colombia","answer2":"Brazil","answer3":"Angola","answer4":"Mozambique","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which word from the inaugural address by Barack Obama was cut out of the speech whilst being broadcast in China?","correctAnswer":"Communism","answer2":"Chinese","answer3":"Tibet","answer4":"Earthquakes","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"What was the name of Wellington's horse?","correctAnswer":"Copenhagen","answer2":"Paris","answer3":"Rome","answer4":"Washington","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Florence Nightingale achieved fame during which war?","correctAnswer":"Crimean","answer2":"First World War","answer3":"Boer War","answer4":"100 Years War","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which animal is not a Chinese year?","correctAnswer":"Crow","answer2":"Ox","answer3":"Pig","answer4":"Monkey","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which animal is not a Chinese year? ","correctAnswer":"Dolphin","answer2":"Dog","answer3":"Monkey","answer4":"Goat","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which English King died in 1553 at the age of 15?","correctAnswer":"Edward VI","answer2":"Edward V","answer3":"Edward VII","answer4":"Edward IV","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"The crown of which New York City landmark was originally built as an airship dock?","correctAnswer":"Empire State Building","answer2":"Chrysler Building","answer3":"Statue of Liberty","answer4":"Trump Tower","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"What was the 1969 war between El Salvador and Honduras called?","correctAnswer":"football","answer2":"cod","answer3":"cola","answer4":"postage stamp","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which English King bought Buckingham Palace?","correctAnswer":"George III","answer2":"George II","answer3":"Charles I","answer4":"Charles II","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which US President said \"I cannot tell a lie\"?","correctAnswer":"George. Washington","answer2":"George W Bush","answer3":"Richard Nixon","answer4":"Bill Clinton","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which language did King George I speak?","correctAnswer":"German","answer2":"Latin","answer3":"French","answer4":"Russian","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which King Harold died during the battle of Hastings?","correctAnswer":"Godwinson","answer2":"Harefoot","answer3":"the Elder","answer4":"Ironside","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which ancient world wonder was found in Giza?","correctAnswer":"Great Pyramid","answer2":"Lighthouse","answer3":"Temple Of Artemis","answer4":"Statue Of Zeus","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"What was Ehrich Weiss better known as?","correctAnswer":"Harry Houdini","answer2":"Charlie Chaplin","answer3":"The Great Suprendo","answer4":"David Copperfield ","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"On which island was Capt Cook killed in 1779?","correctAnswer":"Hawaii","answer2":"Australia","answer3":"New Zealand","answer4":"Moluccan Islands","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"The falsely accused WW I spy Mata Hari was from which country?","correctAnswer":"Holland","answer2":"France","answer3":"India","answer4":"Italy","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which country founded the West India Company?","correctAnswer":"Holland","answer2":"France","answer3":"Germany","answer4":"Spain","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Diana was the Roman goddess of what?","correctAnswer":"Hunting","answer2":"Passion","answer3":"Beauty","answer4":"War","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"What country provided the birthplace of Christopher Columbus?","correctAnswer":"Italy","answer2":"Spain","answer3":"Portugal","answer4":"France","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which English Monarch was the first from the House of Stuart?","correctAnswer":"James I","answer2":"Charles I","answer3":"Henry VII","answer4":"Edward IV","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which English Monarch was succeeded by William III of Orange?","correctAnswer":"James II","answer2":"James I","answer3":"Charles II","answer4":"Mary II","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which English Monarch succeeded Charles II?","correctAnswer":"James II","answer2":"James I","answer3":"William III","answer4":"Mary II","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Who hosted the music radio program The Perfumed Garden?","correctAnswer":"John Peel","answer2":"Noel Edmunds","answer3":"Kenny Everett","answer4":"Vernon Kay","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Joseph Stalin twice ordered the KGB to assassinate which US actor?","correctAnswer":"John Wayne","answer2":"Humphrey Bogart","answer3":"Bob Hope","answer4":"James Cagney","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"The Mau Mau were terrorists in which country late 50s early 60s?","correctAnswer":"Kenya","answer2":"Sudan","answer3":"Malaysia","answer4":"Ghana","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"What was the name of the atom bomb dropped on Hiroshima?","correctAnswer":"Little Boy","answer2":"Bad Boy","answer3":"Fat Boy","answer4":"Good Boy","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which explorers expedition was the first to circumnavigate the earth?","correctAnswer":"Magellan","answer2":"Cook","answer3":"de Gama","answer4":"Cartier","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which English Monarch succeeded William III of Orange?","correctAnswer":"Mary II","answer2":"James II","answer3":"James I","answer4":"Charles II","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which famous outlaws last words were \"That's life\"?","correctAnswer":"Ned Kelly","answer2":"Al Capone","answer3":"Dick Turpin","answer4":"Billy the Kid","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which month of 1987 was weatherman Michael Fish embarrassed for failing to give warning of severe gales?","correctAnswer":"October","answer2":"September","answer3":"December","answer4":"August","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which English Monarch was also known as Old Ironsides","correctAnswer":"Oliver Cromwell","answer2":"Richard Cromwell","answer3":"Charles I","answer4":"Charles II","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"From which country did Bangladesh claim its independence?","correctAnswer":"Pakistan","answer2":"India","answer3":"China","answer4":"Britain","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Where did the 30 years war start and finish?","correctAnswer":"Prague","answer2":"Berlin","answer3":"London","answer4":"Paris","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which member of the British Royal Family was made Deputy Sheriff of Harris County, Texas in 1960?","correctAnswer":"Prince Philip","answer2":"Prince Charles","answer3":"The Queen","answer4":"Prince Andrew","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Who directly succeeded King Edward VI as Monarch of England?","correctAnswer":"Queen Jane","answer2":"Queen Mary I","answer3":"Queen Elizabeth I","answer4":"King James I","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Seti I was the father of which Egyptian?","correctAnswer":"Ramesses II","answer2":"Tutankhamun","answer3":"Nefertiti","answer4":"Cleopatra","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Julius Caesar said \"The die is cast\" after crossing which river?","correctAnswer":"Rubicon","answer2":"Thames","answer3":"Tiber","answer4":"Danube","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"The crossing of which river started a civil war?","correctAnswer":"Rubicon","answer2":"St. Lawrence","answer3":"Avon","answer4":"Danube","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"What kind of march did Gandhi lead?","correctAnswer":"Salt","answer2":"Pepper","answer3":"Sugar","answer4":"Flower","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which city was destroyed by an earthquake in 1906?","correctAnswer":"San Francisco","answer2":"Naples","answer3":"Lisbon","answer4":"Havana","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"What was the name of the flu that killed an estimated 40 million people in 1918?","correctAnswer":"Spanish","answer2":"Asian","answer3":"Hong Kong","answer4":"European","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Olaf Palme was assassinated in 1986. Of which country was he the prime minister?","correctAnswer":"Sweden","answer2":"Norway","answer3":"Finland","answer4":"Denmark","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"What was sometimes used as currency in 18th century Siberia?","correctAnswer":"Tea","answer2":"Coffee","answer3":"Snow","answer4":"Tulips","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"What did Captain Cook call the Islands of Tonga?","correctAnswer":"The Friendly Islands","answer2":"The Scary Islands","answer3":"The Tongan Islands","answer4":"The Cook Islands","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which of these radio programmes did John Peel once present?","correctAnswer":"The perfumed garden","answer2":"The poisoned garden","answer3":"The tendered garden","answer4":"The Musical garden","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which major British newspaper closed down for almost a year in 1978?","correctAnswer":"The Times","answer2":"The Sun","answer3":"The Telegraph","answer4":"The Mirror","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which ancient world wonder was found in Alexandria?","correctAnswer":"The Lighthouse","answer2":"Hanging Gardens","answer3":"Temple Of Artemis","answer4":"Great Pyramid","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"The Rainbow Warrior was what form of transport?","correctAnswer":"Trawler","answer2":"Cruise Ship","answer3":"Tugboat","answer4":"Oil Tanker","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"What was the name of the cat that survived the sinking of the Bismark, HMS Cossack and the HMS Ark Royal in WW II ?","correctAnswer":"Unsinkable Sam","answer2":"Unsinkable Molly Brown","answer3":"Wet Willy","answer4":"Kit Cat","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Marco Polo was a citizen of which city?","correctAnswer":"Venice","answer2":"Rome","answer3":"Florence","answer4":"Naples","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which animal is not a Chinese year?","correctAnswer":"Whale","answer2":"Snake","answer3":"Hare","answer4":"Tiger","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"In history, the highwayman Dick Turpin was hanged in which city?","correctAnswer":"York","answer2":"London","answer3":"Leeds","answer4":"Portsmouth","topic":"history","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many wheels had a hansom cab?","correctAnswer":2,"answer2":3,"answer3":4,"answer4":5,"topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"How many seconds did it take Napoleons surgeon Baron Dominique Larrey to amputate a leg?","correctAnswer":14,"answer2":3,"answer3":32,"answer4":60,"topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"How many swings of the axe did it take to remove Maria Stuarts head?","correctAnswer":15,"answer2":1,"answer3":3,"answer4":35,"topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"How many dollars did the first settlers pay the native Indians for Manhattan Island?","correctAnswer":24,"answer2":4,"answer3":48,"answer4":96,"topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"Concubines excluded, how many wives did a Chinese Emperor have?","correctAnswer":40,"answer2":1,"answer3":13,"answer4":88,"topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"According to legend, how many bears did Davy Crockett kill in 7 months? ","correctAnswer":105,"answer2":7,"answer3":77,"answer4":705,"topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"How old was the Biblical figure Methusalem?","correctAnswer":969,"answer2":844,"answer3":622,"answer4":369,"topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which year were the Salem witchcraft trials?","correctAnswer":1692,"answer2":1581,"answer3":1744,"answer4":1519,"topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which year was the last legal execution of a witch in Scotland?","correctAnswer":1727,"answer2":1827,"answer3":1927,"answer4":1627,"topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which year was the lightning rod invented?","correctAnswer":1752,"answer2":1322,"answer3":1825,"answer4":1901,"topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which year did New York become a US state?","correctAnswer":1788,"answer2":1819,"answer3":1792,"answer4":1837,"topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which year did the first steam ship cross the Atlantic?","correctAnswer":1819,"answer2":1910,"answer3":1859,"answer4":1780,"topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"The age of the railway began in which year with the introduction of the Liverpool-Manchester line?","correctAnswer":1830,"answer2":1800,"answer3":1860,"answer4":1770,"topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which year did the first passenger die in a rail accident?","correctAnswer":1830,"answer2":1850,"answer3":1780,"answer4":1870,"topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which year were postage stamps introduced?","correctAnswer":1840,"answer2":1899,"answer3":1745,"answer4":1650,"topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which year did Texas become a US state?","correctAnswer":1845,"answer2":1912,"answer3":1959,"answer4":1861,"topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"The first weather report in a newspaper appeared in which year?","correctAnswer":1848,"answer2":1788,"answer3":1871,"answer4":1902,"topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which year were blue jeans invented?","correctAnswer":1874,"answer2":1836,"answer3":1902,"answer4":1580,"topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which year was the light bulb invented?","correctAnswer":1880,"answer2":1901,"answer3":1825,"answer4":1911,"topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which year did Oklahoma become a US state?","correctAnswer":1907,"answer2":1889,"answer3":1850,"answer4":1819,"topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which year did New Mexico become a US state?","correctAnswer":1912,"answer2":1867,"answer3":1959,"answer4":1788,"topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which year were false eyelashes invented?","correctAnswer":1916,"answer2":1925,"answer3":1939,"answer4":1888,"topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which year did Charles Lindbergh fly solo across the Atlantic?","correctAnswer":1927,"answer2":1937,"answer3":1917,"answer4":1907,"topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which year was nylon invented?","correctAnswer":1935,"answer2":1885,"answer3":1906,"answer4":1951,"topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which year was the transistor invented?","correctAnswer":1947,"answer2":1844,"answer3":1902,"answer4":1975,"topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which year was the microwave oven invented?","correctAnswer":1947,"answer2":1977,"answer3":1921,"answer4":1982,"topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which year did the hula hoop craze first circle the world?","correctAnswer":1958,"answer2":1963,"answer3":1952,"answer4":1966,"topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which year was the Berlin wall built?","correctAnswer":1961,"answer2":1958,"answer3":1946,"answer4":1965,"topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which year was Nelson Mandela sentenced to life in prison?","correctAnswer":1964,"answer2":1972,"answer3":1956,"answer4":1978,"topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which year did the mini skirt first turn heads?","correctAnswer":1964,"answer2":1968,"answer3":1958,"answer4":1961,"topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which year was the first 'Great Blackout' in the eastern United States and Canada?","correctAnswer":1965,"answer2":1975,"answer3":1955,"answer4":1985,"topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which year was the 747 Jumbo jet introduced?","correctAnswer":1970,"answer2":1964,"answer3":1978,"answer4":1984,"topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"Timber selected from how many fully grown oak trees were needed to build a large 3 decker Royal Navy battle ship in the 18th century?","correctAnswer":3500.0,"answer2":50,"answer3":500,"answer4":1500.0,"topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"In 1970 the 'Blue Flame' became the first car to break which speed barrier?","correctAnswer":"1,000 km hr","answer2":"250 km hr","answer3":"500 km hr","answer4":"1,500 km hr","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"The 'football' or briefcase with the nuclear codes must always be within how many metres of the US President?","correctAnswer":"12 m","answer2":"6 m","answer3":"2 m","answer4":"24 m","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"How long did the Apollo 11 mission last?","correctAnswer":"195 hours 18 min","answer2":"95 hours 18 min","answer3":"295 hours 18 min","answer4":"495 hours 18 min","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"What was the average life expectancy of an Englishman in the middle ages?","correctAnswer":"33 years","answer2":"13 years","answer3":"21 years","answer4":"41 years","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"How long was the war between GB  and Zansibar in 1896?","correctAnswer":"38 min","answer2":"38 sec","answer3":"38 hours","answer4":"38 days","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"How long did the Wright Brothers first flight last?","correctAnswer":"59 sec","answer2":"12 sec","answer3":"3 sec   ","answer4":"24 sec","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"What was the cargo on board the HMS Bounty?","correctAnswer":"Breadfruit","answer2":"Grapefruit","answer3":"Sauerkraut","answer4":"Watermelon","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"Who was Patrick Stewart's best man at his wedding?","correctAnswer":"Brent Spiner","answer2":"William Shatner","answer3":"LeVar Burton","answer4":"Johnathan Frakes","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"Off the coast of which country did the Edmund Fitzgerald sink?","correctAnswer":"Canada","answer2":"Ireland","answer3":"Scotland","answer4":"Australia","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"The press coined which famous pilot 'The Flying Fool' in 1927?","correctAnswer":"Charles Lindbergh","answer2":"Baron von Richtofen","answer3":"Orville Wright","answer4":"Amelia Earhart","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which country did an earthquake kill an estimated 650,000 people in 1976?","correctAnswer":"China","answer2":"Pakistan","answer3":"Mexico","answer4":"Japan","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"Punch editor A P Herbert once wrote a cheque on the side of a what?","correctAnswer":"cow","answer2":"bus","answer3":"taxi","answer4":"egg","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"The USA bought the Virgin islands from which country?","correctAnswer":"Denmark","answer2":"GB","answer3":"Holland","answer4":"France","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which city was never the capital of the USA?","correctAnswer":"Detroit","answer2":"New York ","answer3":"Baltimore","answer4":"Philadelphia","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"Tollbooth was an infamous 18th century prison in which city?","correctAnswer":"Edinburgh","answer2":"Halifax","answer3":"London","answer4":"Bristol","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which queen at one time banned the use of mirrors?","correctAnswer":"Elizabeth I ","answer2":"Elizabeth II ","answer3":"Mary","answer4":"Freddie Mercury","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"How often does Airforce One undergo a complete overhaul or D-Check?","correctAnswer":"every 154 days","answer2":"every 54 days","answer3":"every 254 days","answer4":"every 354 days","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"In the 1930s, what was the 'Phalange'?","correctAnswer":"Fascist movement in Spain","answer2":"Secret police in Italy","answer3":"Abstract art movement","answer4":"Dance craze","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"The NAZIS declared war on which country 3 March 1945?","correctAnswer":"Finland","answer2":"Japan","answer3":"France","answer4":"Italy","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"What did the Roman Catholic church condemned in the 16th century?","correctAnswer":"fork","answer2":"spoon","answer3":"corkscrew","answer4":"knife","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"Off the coast of which country did the Amoco Cadiz sink?","correctAnswer":"France","answer2":"USA","answer3":"Spain","answer4":"South Africa","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"The Roman province Aquitania was found in which modern day country?","correctAnswer":"France","answer2":"Scotland","answer3":"Portugal","answer4":"Austria","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which explorer first entered San Francisco Bay in 1579?","correctAnswer":"Francis Drake","answer2":"Juan Ponce de Leon","answer3":"Henry Hudson","answer4":"Amerigo Vespucci","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"Baby Doc Duvalier was the dictator of which country?","correctAnswer":"Haiti","answer2":"Senegal","answer3":"Vietnam","answer4":"Algeria","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"Herodotus is known as the father of what?","correctAnswer":"History","answer2":"Medicine","answer3":"Theatre","answer4":"Music","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"Between which two countries was the 1969 'Football War'?","correctAnswer":"Honduras and El Salvador","answer2":"Brazil and Argentina","answer3":"Algeria and Tunisia","answer4":" Chile and Peru ","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"Off the coast of which country did the QE I sink?","correctAnswer":"Hong Kong","answer2":"USA","answer3":"Brazil","answer4":"Spain","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which ship sank in the Denmark Strait?","correctAnswer":"Hood","answer2":"Bismark","answer3":"Titanic","answer4":"Exon Valdez","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which country invented Venetian Blinds?","correctAnswer":"Japan","answer2":"Italy","answer3":"France","answer4":"USA","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"Who was the captain of PT 109?","correctAnswer":"JFK","answer2":"Ronald Reagan","answer3":"George Bush sr","answer4":"Gerald Ford","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"Who was William Shatner's best man at his wedding?","correctAnswer":"Leonard Nimoy","answer2":"Brent Spiner","answer3":"DeForest Kelley","answer4":"James Doohan","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which magazine first published photos of a human embryo in 1965?","correctAnswer":"Life","answer2":"Time","answer3":"Newsweek","answer4":"Cosmopolitan ","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which PM played a role in the development of soft ice cream?","correctAnswer":"Margret Thatcher ","answer2":"Tony Blair","answer3":"Winston Churchill ","answer4":"William Pitt","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"Botany Bay was the first penal colony in which Australian state?","correctAnswer":"New South Wales","answer2":"Tasmania","answer3":"South Australia","answer4":"Queensland","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which kind of animal did Florence Nightingale often carry around in her pocket?     ","correctAnswer":"Owl","answer2":"Snake","answer3":"Puppy","answer4":"Kitten","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which is the oldest airline in the English-speaking world?","correctAnswer":"Quantas","answer2":"British Airways","answer3":"American Airlines","answer4":"Air Lingus","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"What kind of animal was the germanic goddess of the spring?","correctAnswer":"rabbit","answer2":"fox","answer3":"bluebird","answer4":"wolf","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"Between 1807 and 1821 the capital of Portugal was found in which city?","correctAnswer":"Rio de Janeiro","answer2":"London","answer3":"Madrid","answer4":"Goa","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"Who was Australia's longest serving Prime Minister?","correctAnswer":"Robert Menzies","answer2":"John Howard","answer3":"Gough Whitlam","answer4":"Bob Hawke","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"Who was the first man to claim he reach the North Pole in 1909?","correctAnswer":"Robert Peary","answer2":"Roald Amundsen","answer3":"Robert Scott","answer4":"Admiral Halsey","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"The Roman province Lusitania was found in which modern day country?","correctAnswer":"Spain","answer2":"France","answer3":"Ireland","answer4":"Germany","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which Sunday newspaper, in 1924, published the first crossword to appear in a British Newspaper?","correctAnswer":"Sunday Express","answer2":"Sunday Times","answer3":"The Observer","answer4":"Sunday Mirror","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which Prime Minister helped invent soft ice-cream?","correctAnswer":"Thatcher","answer2":"Wilson","answer3":"Major","answer4":"Callaghan","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"What was TIME magazines man of the year in 1982?","correctAnswer":"The Computer ","answer2":"The Red Cross","answer3":"The Automobile","answer4":"NASA","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World was found in Halicarnassus?","correctAnswer":"The Mausoleum","answer2":"The Temple of Artemis","answer3":"The Hanging Gardens","answer4":"The Lighthouse","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"Off the coast of which country did the USS Arizona sink?","correctAnswer":"USA","answer2":"Australia","answer3":"Ireland","answer4":"Canada","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"What name did the Vikings give to present day Newfoundland?","correctAnswer":"Vinland","answer2":"Graceland","answer3":"No mans Land","answer4":"Ice Land","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which US state did Sir Walter Raleigh name?","correctAnswer":"Virginia","answer2":"Massachusetts","answer3":"Rhode Island","answer4":"Florida","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"Who was Ronald Reagan's best man at his wedding?","correctAnswer":"William Holden","answer2":"Cary Grant","answer3":"Charlie Chaplin","answer4":"Humphrey Bogart","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which Thomas was executed alongside Guy Fawkes in November 1605?","correctAnswer":"Winter","answer2":"May","answer3":"Summer","answer4":"March","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which general defeated the French in Canada?","correctAnswer":"Wolfe","answer2":"Hawke","answer3":"Lambe","answer4":"Hogge","topic":"history","difficulty":3},{"question":"How many ghosts visit Scrooge in A Christmas Carol?","correctAnswer":4,"answer2":3,"answer3":2,"answer4":5,"topic":"literature","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which female novelist wrote the book Black Beauty?","correctAnswer":"Anna Sewell","answer2":"Barbara Cartland","answer3":"Enid Blyton","answer4":"Dorothy L Sayers","topic":"literature","difficulty":1},{"question":"What was the name of Roy Rogers' pet dog?","correctAnswer":"Bullet","answer2":"Fido","answer3":"Lightening","answer4":"Dog Rogers","topic":"literature","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which book begins with the line \"Most motorcars are conglomerations....\" ?","correctAnswer":"Chitty Chitty Bang Bang","answer2":"The Little Engine That Could","answer3":"War of the Worlds","answer4":"Mary Poppins","topic":"literature","difficulty":1},{"question":"Who wrote 'a clockwork orange'?","correctAnswer":"Anthony Burgess","answer2":"Arnold Burgess","answer3":"Anthony Hopkins","answer4":"Arnold Hopkins","topic":"literature","difficulty":1},{"question":"What was Eric Blair’s pen name?","correctAnswer":"George Orwell","answer2":"H.G. Wells","answer3":"John Steinbeck","answer4":"Charles Dickens","topic":"literature","difficulty":1},{"question":"What was the name of the dog of Dennis the menace?","correctAnswer":"Gnasher","answer2":"Basher","answer3":"Thrasher","answer4":"Smasher","topic":"literature","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which is the longest of Shakespeare’s plays?","correctAnswer":"Hamlet","answer2":"MacBeth","answer3":"2 Gentlemen of Verona","answer4":"Romeo and Juliet","topic":"literature","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which of the following is not a Romance author?","correctAnswer":"Harold Robbins","answer2":"Barbara Cartland","answer3":"Danielle Steel","answer4":"Jackie Collins","topic":"literature","difficulty":1},{"question":"What John Spyri story is about a girl who lives in the Alps?","correctAnswer":"Heidi","answer2":"Annie","answer3":"Emily","answer4":"Carmen","topic":"literature","difficulty":1},{"question":"In which month did Samuel Pepys begin his famous diary?","correctAnswer":"January","answer2":"March","answer3":"May","answer4":"July","topic":"literature","difficulty":1},{"question":"At which railway station does one board the 'Hogwarts Express'?","correctAnswer":"Kings Cross","answer2":"Waterloo","answer3":"Victoria","answer4":"Charing Cross","topic":"literature","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which of the following is not a childrens author?","correctAnswer":"Michael Crichton","answer2":"Dr. Seuss","answer3":"Enid Blyton","answer4":"Roger Hargreaves","topic":"literature","difficulty":1},{"question":"What was the name of Sherlock Holmes house keeper?","correctAnswer":"Mrs Hudson","answer2":"Mrs Sippi","answer3":"Miss Mayweather","answer4":"Mrs Wilson","topic":"literature","difficulty":1},{"question":"Michael Bond was the creator of which bear?","correctAnswer":"Paddington","answer2":"Yogi","answer3":"Pooh","answer4":"Baloo","topic":"literature","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which book begins with the line \"All children except one, grow up....\" ?","correctAnswer":"Peter Pan","answer2":"Mary Poppins","answer3":"The Jungle Book","answer4":"The lion. the witch and the wardrobe","topic":"literature","difficulty":1},{"question":"Whose nose grew when he told a lie?","correctAnswer":"Pinocchio","answer2":"Dumbo","answer3":"Jeffrey Archer","answer4":"Peter Pan","topic":"literature","difficulty":1},{"question":"Carlo Collodi created which famous children's character?","correctAnswer":"Pinocchio","answer2":"Dumbo","answer3":"Snow White","answer4":"Peter Pan","topic":"literature","difficulty":1},{"question":"What is Dick Grayson better known as?","correctAnswer":"Robin","answer2":"Batman","answer3":"Joker","answer4":"Alfred","topic":"literature","difficulty":1},{"question":"Where was William Shakespeare born?","correctAnswer":"Stratford Upon Avon","answer2":"Bath","answer3":"Bradford","answer4":"Kingston Upon Thames","topic":"literature","difficulty":1},{"question":"What is the subtitle of Peter Pan?","correctAnswer":"The Boy Who Wouldn’t Grow Up","answer2":"The Boy With The Growing Nose","answer3":"The Puppet That Came Alive","answer4":"The Boy Who Lied","topic":"literature","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which book begins with the line \"Dorothy lived in the midst....\" ?","correctAnswer":"The Wonderful Wizard of Oz","answer2":"Mary Poppins","answer3":"The Thorn Birds","answer4":"Mists of Avalon","topic":"literature","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which of the following is the best-selling fiction author of all time?","correctAnswer":"William Shakespeare","answer2":"Agatha Christie","answer3":"Barbara Cartland","answer4":"Harold Robbins","topic":"literature","difficulty":1},{"question":"How many Bronte sisters were there?","correctAnswer":3,"answer2":2,"answer3":4,"answer4":5,"topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many children were in Enid Blytons the famous five?","correctAnswer":4,"answer2":5,"answer3":6,"answer4":3,"topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Winston Smith is the central character in which book?","correctAnswer":1984,"answer2":"The Time Machine","answer3":"Dune","answer4":"The Day Of The Triffids","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many rode into Tennyson's 'valley of death'?","correctAnswer":600,"answer2":1000,"answer3":6000,"answer4":100,"topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"How old was Adrian Mole?","correctAnswer":"13 and 3 quarters","answer2":"13 and a half","answer3":"13 and 3 fifths","answer4":"13 and 2 thirds","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"What was the name of inn in Treasure Island?","correctAnswer":"Admiral Benbow","answer2":"Captain Benbow","answer3":"Corporal Benbow","answer4":"Officer Benbow","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Who wrote \"don't count your chickens before they are hatched\"?","correctAnswer":"Aesop","answer2":"Shakespeare","answer3":"Ben  Franklin","answer4":"Chaucer","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which of the following is the second best-selling fiction author of all time?","correctAnswer":"Agatha Christie","answer2":"William Shakespeare","answer3":"Barbara Cartland","answer4":"Harold Robbins","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Who wrote 'The Count of Monte Christo'?","correctAnswer":"Alexandre Dumas","answer2":"Victor Hugo","answer3":"Nathaniel Hawthorne","answer4":"Herman Melville","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which name is not a Steven King book?","correctAnswer":"Cacy","answer2":"Carrie","answer3":"Cujo ","answer4":"Christine","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which book begins with the line \"These two very old people are the father and mother of Mr Bucket...\"?","correctAnswer":"Charlie and the Chocolate Factory","answer2":"Peter Pan","answer3":"Mary Poppins","answer4":"Treasure Island","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which of the following is not visited by Gulliver in Gulliver's Travels?","correctAnswer":"China","answer2":"Japan","answer3":"Lilliput","answer4":"Laputa","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Who wrote 'Moll Flanders'?","correctAnswer":"Daniel DeFoe","answer2":"Johnathan Swift","answer3":"Voltaire","answer4":"Henry Fielding","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Who wrote In The Beginning I Used To Be An Animal But I'm Alright Now?","correctAnswer":"Eric Burdon","answer2":"Wayne Rooney","answer3":"Scary Spice","answer4":"Vinnie Jones","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"What is the complete title of Mary Shelley's Frankenstein?","correctAnswer":"Frankenstein or The modern Prometheus","answer2":"Frankenstein or The modern genesis","answer3":"Frankenstein or The modern satan","answer4":"Frankenstein or The modern phoenix","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Who wrote 'Pygmalion'?","correctAnswer":"G B Shaw","answer2":"Mark Twain","answer3":"Tolstoj","answer4":"Emily Bronte","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which of these writers died in 1400?","correctAnswer":"Geoffrey Chaucer","answer2":"William Shakespeare","answer3":"Daniel DeFoe","answer4":"Samuel Johnson","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"What was Mary Ann Evans pen name?","correctAnswer":"George Eliot","answer2":"George Orwell","answer3":"George Sand","answer4":"George Bernard Shaw","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Who wrote 'Tom Jones'?","correctAnswer":"Henry Fielding","answer2":"Johnathan Swift","answer3":"Daniel DeFoe","answer4":"Herman Melville","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Aldous Huxley's book Brave New World was banned in which country?","correctAnswer":"Ireland","answer2":"Canada","answer3":"South Africa","answer4":"USA","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Who wrote 'I Robot'?","correctAnswer":"Isaac Asimov","answer2":"Jules Verne","answer3":"H G Wells","answer4":"Douglas Adams","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Who was Rowena's husband?","correctAnswer":"Ivanhoe","answer2":"Robin Hood","answer3":"Dick Turpin","answer4":"Macbeth","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Who wrote 'Peter Pan'?","correctAnswer":"J M Barrie","answer2":"Rudyard Kipling","answer3":"Lewis Carroll","answer4":"Carlo Collodi","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Who wrote the book The Last Of The Mohicans?","correctAnswer":"James Fenimore Cooper","answer2":"H.G. Wells","answer3":"Jules Verne","answer4":"Sir Walter Scott","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which book begins with the line \" The great fish moved silently...\" ?","correctAnswer":"Jaws","answer2":"Moby Dick","answer3":"The Old Man and the Sea","answer4":"The Shipping News","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Who wrote 'The Spy Who Came In From The Cold'?","correctAnswer":"John le Carre","answer2":"Ian Fleming","answer3":"Henning Mankell","answer4":"Arthur Conan Doyle","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Mother Raksha is a character in which childrens book?","correctAnswer":"Jungle Book","answer2":"The Wonderful Wizard Of Oz","answer3":"The Wind in the Willows","answer4":"Peter Pan","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Uther Pendragon was which mans father?","correctAnswer":"King Arthur","answer2":"Dick Turpin","answer3":"Robin Hood","answer4":"Ivanhoe","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Oliver Mellors is a central character in which novel?","correctAnswer":"Lady Chatterley's Lover","answer2":"The Great Gatsby","answer3":"Animal Farm","answer4":"The World According To Garp","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Totally Frank is which Frank's autobiography?","correctAnswer":"Lampard","answer2":"Sinatra","answer3":"Zappa","answer4":"Howard","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Who wrote the popular Simon Templar books?","correctAnswer":"Leslie Charteris","answer2":"Dorothy L Sayers","answer3":"John le Carre","answer4":"Raymond Chandler","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"What were the cities in Dickens’s A Tale Of Two Cities?","correctAnswer":"London and Paris","answer2":"Rome and Florence","answer3":"Venice and Rome","answer4":"Paris and Florence","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Who is a bat in Jungle Book?","correctAnswer":"Mang","answer2":"Hang","answer3":"Bang","answer4":"Fang","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Who wrote 'The Mists of Avalon'?","correctAnswer":"Marion Zimmer Bradley","answer2":"J R R Tolkien","answer3":"Joanne K Rowling","answer4":"Terry Pratchett","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"What was Samuel Langhorne Clemens pen name?","correctAnswer":"Mark Twain","answer2":"Novalis","answer3":"Jack London","answer4":"Joseph Conrad","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"What was the name of the paranoid android in Hitch Hikers Guide to the Galaxy?","correctAnswer":"Marvin","answer2":"Gort","answer3":"Wayne","answer4":"Robby","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"The Count of Monte Christo was in love with which woman?","correctAnswer":"Mercedes","answer2":"Porsche","answer3":"Lancia","answer4":"Cadillac","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"What are the cannibalistic beasts called in H.G. Wells book The Time Machine?","correctAnswer":"Morlocks","answer2":"Warlocks","answer3":"Yahoos","answer4":"Triffids","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Whose autobiography was entitled 'The Long Walk To Freedom'?","correctAnswer":"Nelson Mandela","answer2":"Mahatma Gandhi","answer3":"Lenin","answer4":"Martin Luther King","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Who does Mr Brownlow rescue?","correctAnswer":"Oliver Twist","answer2":"Tom Jones","answer3":"Huckleberry Finn","answer4":"Tom Brown","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which nationality is best-selling author Paulo Coelho?","correctAnswer":"Portuguese","answer2":"Spanish","answer3":"French","answer4":"Italian","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"What is comic book hero Roy of the Rovers' surname?","correctAnswer":"Race","answer2":"Run","answer3":"Rave","answer4":"Rover","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which Adams wrote Watership Down?","correctAnswer":"Richard","answer2":"Douglas","answer3":"Tony","answer4":"Morticia","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which king said \"A horse, a horse! my kingdom for a horse!\"?","correctAnswer":"Richard III","answer2":"Henry VIII","answer3":"Wenceslas","answer4":"Arthur","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Who wrote 'Treasure Island'?","correctAnswer":"Robert Louis Stevenson","answer2":"H G Wells","answer3":"Jack London","answer4":"Sir Walter Scott","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Who wrote the book 'Dr Jekyll and Mr Hyde'?","correctAnswer":"Robert Louis Stevenson","answer2":"Sir Walter Scott","answer3":"Iian Banks","answer4":"Alister Maclean","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"What Was the Title Of Alex Haleys Most Famous Work?","correctAnswer":"Roots","answer2":"Boots","answer3":"Coots","answer4":"Toots","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which novel begins with the line \"Early in the spring of 1750....\" ?","correctAnswer":"Roots","answer2":"Tom Jones","answer3":"The Great Gatsby","answer4":"I, Claudius","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"What school does Tom attend in Tom Brown’s school days?","correctAnswer":"Rugby","answer2":"Eton","answer3":"Harrow","answer4":"Dulwich","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Who wrote the play 'Waiting for Godot'?","correctAnswer":"Samuel Beckett","answer2":"George Bernard Shaw","answer3":"Andrew Lloyd Webber","answer4":"Vladimir Nabokov","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"The jealous Athena turned Arachne into which kind of animal?","correctAnswer":"spider","answer2":"snake","answer3":"donkey","answer4":"rat","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"What was the title of George Bernard Shaw’s play about Joan of Arc?","correctAnswer":"St Joan","answer2":"Joan of Arc","answer3":"Joan D'arc","answer4":"Our Joan","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which of the following authors are not in the top ten best-selling literature authors of all time?","correctAnswer":"Stephen King","answer2":"Agatha Christie","answer3":"Danielle Steel","answer4":"Gilbert Patten","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Holden Caulfield is the main character in which book?","correctAnswer":"The Catcher In The Rye","answer2":"Catch 22","answer3":"Moby Dick","answer4":1984,"topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which book begins with the line \"Once there were four children whose names were Peter, Susan, Edmond, and Lucy....\"?","correctAnswer":"The Lion, the Witch and the Wardrobe","answer2":"Peter Pan","answer3":"Mary Poppins","answer4":"The Swiss Family Robinson","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Shylock is a character in which Shakespeare play?","correctAnswer":"The Merchant Of Venice","answer2":"Measure For Measure","answer3":"Othello","answer4":"The Comedy Of Errors","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"In The Lord of the Rings, what is the name of the inn in Bree?","correctAnswer":"The Prancing Pony","answer2":"The Red Stallion","answer3":"The Merry Mare","answer4":"The Spotted Gelding","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which book would one find the childlike human species named Elois?","correctAnswer":"The Time Machine","answer2":"Day Of The Triffids","answer3":"Brave New World","answer4":"Dune","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which book would one find the trog like human species named Morlocks?","correctAnswer":"The Time Machine","answer2":"Dune","answer3":"Brave New World","answer4":"The Day Of The Triffids","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Who wrote 'The Hunchback of Notre Dame'?","correctAnswer":"Victor Hugo","answer2":"Gustave Flaubert","answer3":"Voltaire","answer4":"Alexandre Dumas","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Who wrote 'Mrs Dalloway'?","correctAnswer":"Virginia Woolf","answer2":"James Joyce","answer3":"D H Lawrence","answer4":"Graham Greene","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"Who wrote 'The Lord of the Flies'?","correctAnswer":"William Golding","answer2":"George Orwell","answer3":"Aldous Huxley","answer4":"Joseph Conrad","topic":"literature","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many tasks did Hercules have to fulfill?","correctAnswer":12,"answer2":6,"answer3":8,"answer4":24,"topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"How long did Robinson Crusoe spend on the island?","correctAnswer":"28 years, 2 months and 19 days","answer2":"2 years, 8 months and 12 days","answer3":"55 years, 4 months and 3 days","answer4":"7 years, 9 months and 22 days","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"Who was 'The Once and Future King'?","correctAnswer":"Arthur","answer2":"Elvis","answer3":"Idi Amin","answer4":"Arargon","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which sport is referred to in ‘Antony and Cleopatra’?","correctAnswer":"Billiards","answer2":"Snooker","answer3":"Pool","answer4":"Darts","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"Who is not one of King Lears daughters?","correctAnswer":"Celia","answer2":"Cordelia","answer3":"Goneril","answer4":"Regan","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"Lewis Carroll's book Alice's Adventures in Wonderland was banned in which country?","correctAnswer":"China","answer2":"USA","answer3":"France","answer4":"Ireland","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which book begins with the line \"Not too long ago, a monster came to the small town of Castle Rock...\" ?","correctAnswer":"Cujo","answer2":"Harry Potter and the Scorcerer's Stone","answer3":"Bram Stoker's Dracula","answer4":"Frankenstein's Monster","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"In Which Dickens Novel Does Mr Micawber Appear?","correctAnswer":"David Copperfield","answer2":"Oliver Twist","answer3":"A Christmas carol","answer4":"Great Expectations","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"Who wrote the book The Moons A Balloon?","correctAnswer":"David Niven","answer2":"H.G. Wells","answer3":"Jules Verne","answer4":"Julie Andrews","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"What was Casanova's first name?","correctAnswer":"Giacoma","answer2":"Alberto","answer3":"Benito","answer4":"Francesco","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which novel begins with the line \"My father's family name being Pirrip....\"?","correctAnswer":"Great Expectations","answer2":"Charlie and the Chocalate Factory","answer3":"Kidnapped","answer4":"Little Women","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which book would one find the character named 'Pip'?","correctAnswer":"Great Expectations","answer2":"Wind in the Willows","answer3":"Jurassic Park","answer4":"Rob Roy","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"What is the name of the cat in Shakespeare's Macbeth?","correctAnswer":"Greymalkin","answer2":"Tybalt","answer3":"Tao","answer4":"Kitty","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"Who wrote 'Finnegan's Wake'?","correctAnswer":"James Joyce","answer2":"Bram Stocker","answer3":"W B Yeats","answer4":"Samuel Beckett","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"What are the names of the two main characters in Diana Gabaldon's highland saga novels?","correctAnswer":"Jamie and Claire","answer2":"Fergus and Fiona","answer3":"Rab and Elizabeth","answer4":"Hamish and Maggie","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"Who wrote The Day of the Triffids?","correctAnswer":"John Wyndam","answer2":"Stephen King","answer3":"Douglas Adams","answer4":"Jules Verne","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which book begins with the line \"I will begin the story of my adventures....\" ?","correctAnswer":"Kidnapped","answer2":"Roots","answer3":"Kim","answer4":"Mary Poppins","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"Dan Brown's book The Da Vinci Code was banned in which country?","correctAnswer":"Lebanon","answer2":"Ireland","answer3":"Poland","answer4":"Italy","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which book begins with the line \"Even in high summer, Tintagel was a haunted place...\" ?","correctAnswer":"Mists of Avalon","answer2":"The Once and Future King","answer3":"The Wonderful Wizard of Oz","answer4":"Rosemary's Baby","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"Who lives at Number Four Privat Drive?","correctAnswer":"Mr and Mrs Dursley","answer2":"Toad of Toad Hall","answer3":"Mary Poppins","answer4":"Winnie-The-Pooh","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"What is the name of the man servant in 'Around the world in 80 days'?","correctAnswer":"Pas Partout","answer2":"Cato","answer3":"Giles","answer4":"Machu Picchu","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"What is the name of the ship in 'Moby Dick'?","correctAnswer":"Pequod","answer2":"Essex","answer3":"Boston","answer4":"Surprise","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"Mr Darcy is an arrogant gentleman in which novel?","correctAnswer":"Pride and Prejudice","answer2":"A Passage to India","answer3":"Animal Farm","answer4":"The Great Gatsby","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which novel begins with the line \"Last night I dreamt I went to Manderly again....\" ?","correctAnswer":"Rebecca","answer2":"Little Women","answer3":"Trainspotting","answer4":"Roots","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"Who wrote the poem A Red Red Rose?","correctAnswer":"Robert Burns","answer2":"Shakespeare","answer3":"Dante","answer4":"Stephen King","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"What is the name of Don Quixote's horse?","correctAnswer":"Rosinate","answer2":"Betty","answer3":"Isabella","answer4":"Theresa","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"Who wrote the poem The Lady of the Lake?","correctAnswer":"Sir Walter Scott","answer2":"T.S. Eliot","answer3":"King Henry VIII","answer4":"Shakespeare","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which town did Tom Sawyer live?","correctAnswer":"St Petersburg","answer2":"Bern","answer3":"Hamburg","answer4":"Rome","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which cartoonist created Spider Man?","correctAnswer":"Steve Ditko","answer2":"Walt Disney","answer3":"Gary Larson","answer4":"Bob Montana","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which novel begins with the line \"It was the best of times....\" ?","correctAnswer":"Tale of Two Cities","answer2":"Rebecca","answer3":"Trainspotting","answer4":"Chitty Chitty Bang Bang","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which book begins with the line \"The summer my father bought the bear...\" ?","correctAnswer":"The Hotel New Hampshire","answer2":"The Jungle Book","answer3":"The Godfather","answer4":"Trainspotting","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which book begins with the line \"Samuel Spade's jaw was long and bony....\" ?","correctAnswer":"The Maltese Falcon","answer2":"Jaws","answer3":"Harry Potter and the Sorcerer's Stone","answer4":"The Last of the Mohicans","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which book begins with the line \"The Duchy of Grand Fenwick...\" ?","correctAnswer":"The Mouse that Roared","answer2":"Chitty Chitty Bang Bang","answer3":"Kim","answer4":"Harry Potter and the Sorcerer's Stone","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"The title of which Pink Floyd album is also a chapter in 'The Wind In The Willows'?","correctAnswer":"The Piper At The Gates Of Dawn","answer2":"Wish You Were Here","answer3":"Meddle","answer4":"Animals","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which book begins with the line \" \"Hello, ship\" Jake Holman said under his breath...\" ?","correctAnswer":"The Sand Pebbles","answer2":"Moby Dick","answer3":"The Shipping News","answer4":"A Night to Remember","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which book begins with the line \"The American handed Leamus another cup of coffee....\" ?","correctAnswer":"The Spy Who Came In From The Cold","answer2":"The Maltese Falcon","answer3":"The Godfather","answer4":"The Eye Of The Needle","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which book begins with the line \"For many days we had been tempest tossed....\" ?","correctAnswer":"The Swiss Family Robinson","answer2":"Moby Dick","answer3":"The Shipping News","answer4":"Robinson Crusoe","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which novel begins with the line \"On December 8th, 1915, Maggie Cleary had her fourth birthday....\" ?","correctAnswer":"The Thorn Birds","answer2":"The Hotel New Hampshire","answer3":"Roots","answer4":"Little Women","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"Who wrote 'Utopia' in 1516?","correctAnswer":"Thomas More","answer2":"William Shakespeare","answer3":"Christopher Marlowe","answer4":"Francis Bacon","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which book is there an inn called Admiral Benbow?","correctAnswer":"Treasure Island","answer2":"Peter Pan","answer3":"Lord of the Rings","answer4":"Gullivers Travels","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"In the book The Last Of The Mohicans what was the name of Chingachgook's only son?","correctAnswer":"Uncas","answer2":"Mingo","answer3":"Lightfoot","answer4":"Magua","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which Italian city do Romeo and Juliet live?","correctAnswer":"Verona","answer2":"Naples","answer3":"Milano","answer4":"Pisa","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which two men are waiting for Godot?","correctAnswer":"Vladimir and Estragon","answer2":"Bob and Ted","answer3":"Benno and Babe","answer4":"Pumpkin and Honey Bunny","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which former conservative leader wrote a biography on William Wilberforce in 2007?","correctAnswer":"William Hague","answer2":"John Major","answer3":"Iain Duncan Smith","answer4":"Michael Howard","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which Prime Minister won a Nobel prize for literature?","correctAnswer":"Winston Churchill","answer2":"William Pitt","answer3":"Margret Thatcher","answer4":"Tony Blair","topic":"literature","difficulty":3},{"question":"The jellyfish consists of how much water?","correctAnswer":"95%","answer2":"85%","answer3":"75%","answer4":"65%","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"How many moons does Earth have?","correctAnswer":1,"answer2":0,"answer3":2,"answer4":8,"topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"How many atoms are there in a molecule of water?","correctAnswer":3,"answer2":2,"answer3":4,"answer4":1,"topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"Cows have how many stomachs?","correctAnswer":4,"answer2":1,"answer3":2,"answer4":3,"topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"How many wisdom teeth does the average adult have?","correctAnswer":4,"answer2":6,"answer3":8,"answer4":2,"topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"The octal numbering system consistes of how many digits?","correctAnswer":8,"answer2":2,"answer3":4,"answer4":6,"topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"How many legs does a spider have?","correctAnswer":8,"answer2":6,"answer3":10,"answer4":12,"topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"How many sides does a Nonogon have?","correctAnswer":9,"answer2":19,"answer3":0,"answer4":99,"topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"In which year did Pfizer Inc introduce it's Viagra drug to the market?","correctAnswer":1997,"answer2":1987,"answer3":1977,"answer4":2007,"topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"The binary system of numbers uses which two digits?","correctAnswer":"1 and 0","answer2":"1 and 2","answer3":"1 and 10","answer4":"10 and 100","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"How many millimetres are there in one inch?","correctAnswer":"25.4 mm","answer2":"10.4 mm","answer3":"250.4 mm","answer4":"100.4 mm","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which scientist was born in Germany in 1879, became a Swiss citizen in 1901 and later became a US citizen in 1940?","correctAnswer":"Albert Einstein","answer2":"Max Planck","answer3":"Niels Bohr","answer4":"Ludwig Boltzmann","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"What lives in a Formicarium?","correctAnswer":"Ants","answer2":"Turtles","answer3":"Apes","answer4":"Butterflies","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"What is removed during an appendectomy?","correctAnswer":"Appendix","answer2":"Bone Marrow","answer3":"Kidney","answer4":"Tonsils","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"Who first argued that the world was not flat? ","correctAnswer":"Aristotle","answer2":"Columbus","answer3":"Archimedes","answer4":"Magellan","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"Where did the dingo originate?","correctAnswer":"Australia","answer2":"Africa","answer3":"Asia","answer4":"Europe","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which of the following colours would make you appear the slimest? ","correctAnswer":"Black","answer2":"White","answer3":"Pink","answer4":"Orange","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"What is classified by the A B O system?","correctAnswer":"Blood","answer2":"Skin Colour","answer3":"Fingerprints","answer4":"Genetics","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"What is the loudest animal on earth?","correctAnswer":"Blue whale","answer2":"Cricket","answer3":"Human","answer4":"Howler monkey","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"What is the name of the small tracking file left by websites on your computer?","correctAnswer":"Cookie","answer2":"Worm","answer3":"Spider","answer4":"Trojan","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"What can't a Giraffe do?","correctAnswer":"cough","answer2":"run","answer3":"sleep","answer4":"hear","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"An Aberdeen Angus is a type of what?","correctAnswer":"Cow","answer2":"Dog","answer3":"Pig","answer4":"Plant","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"What is the chemical symbol for Chromium?","correctAnswer":"Cr","answer2":"Ch","answer3":"Kr","answer4":"Cm","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"What was the name of the supercomputer that defeated chess master Garri Kasparov in 1997?","correctAnswer":"Deep Blue","answer2":"Deep Thought","answer3":"Deep Waters","answer4":"Deep End","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which of the following animals is believed to be the first to be domesticated?","correctAnswer":"Dog","answer2":"Cat","answer3":"Cow","answer4":"Rabbit","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"What does a Joule unit measure?","correctAnswer":"Energy","answer2":"Work","answer3":"Pressure","answer4":"Light","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"A tortoiseshell cat is most likely what?","correctAnswer":"Female","answer2":"Deaf","answer3":"Blind","answer4":"Male","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"Pyrophobia is the fear of what?","correctAnswer":"Fire","answer2":"Thunder","answer3":"Skyscrapers","answer4":"Plastic","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"According to Newton, mass times acceleration is equal to what?","correctAnswer":"Force","answer2":"Power","answer3":"Velocity","answer4":"Torque","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"What does a Hertz unit measure?","correctAnswer":"Frequency","answer2":"Energy","answer3":"Pressure ","answer4":"Radioactivity","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"If you had rubella what would you have caught?","correctAnswer":"German measles","answer2":"Chicken Pox","answer3":"Whooping cough","answer4":"Mumps","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which country introduced the worlds first diesel locomotive in 1912?","correctAnswer":"Germany","answer2":"United Kingdom","answer3":"Unites States","answer4":"France","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which of the following is a metal that will not rust?","correctAnswer":"Gold","answer2":"Silver","answer3":"Nickel","answer4":"Zinc","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"Alopecia describes a person with a lack of what?","correctAnswer":"Hair","answer2":"Red blood cells","answer3":"teeth","answer4":"Memory","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"Christopher Cockerel invented what?","correctAnswer":"Hovercraft","answer2":"Cats Eyes on the road","answer3":"Helecopter","answer4":"Catamaran  ","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which is the largest planet in our solar system?","correctAnswer":"Jupiter","answer2":"Saturn","answer3":"Uranus","answer4":"Earth","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"Where in your body is your patella?","correctAnswer":"Knee","answer2":"Elbow","answer3":"Neck","answer4":"Foot","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"Where in the body is the Patella?","correctAnswer":"Knee","answer2":"Shoulder","answer3":"Hip","answer4":"Skull","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which of the following metals is in a liquid state at room temperature","correctAnswer":"Mercury","answer2":"Uranium","answer3":"Sodium","answer4":"Tungsten","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"What is the chemical symbol for Sodium?","correctAnswer":"Na","answer2":"N","answer3":"So","answer4":"S","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which is the most common gas in the atmosphere?","correctAnswer":"Nitrogen","answer2":"Oxygen","answer3":"Helium","answer4":"Carbon Dioxide","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"What is the most common blood type in humans?","correctAnswer":"O","answer2":"A","answer3":"A+","answer4":"A-","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"What is not a primary colour?","correctAnswer":"orange","answer2":"red","answer3":"yellow","answer4":"blue","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"What do botanists study?","correctAnswer":"Plants","answer2":"Biology","answer3":"Dentistry","answer4":"Fossils","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"K is the chemical symbol for which element?","correctAnswer":"Potassium","answer2":"Chromium","answer3":"Sodium","answer4":"Carbon","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"What plant does the Colorado beetle attack?","correctAnswer":"Potato","answer2":"Carrot","answer3":"Cabbage","answer4":"Lettuce","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"Mammals of the Order Marsupialia have what unique feature?","correctAnswer":"Pouches","answer2":"Night vision","answer3":"Webbed feet","answer4":"Powerful legs","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"What does a Pascal unit measure?","correctAnswer":"Pressure","answer2":"Light","answer3":"Radioactivity","answer4":"Heat","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"Na is the chemical symbol for which element?","correctAnswer":"Sodium","answer2":"Nitrogen","answer3":"Potassium","answer4":"Neon","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"With which name do we refer to a male cat?","correctAnswer":"Tomcat","answer2":"Bobcat","answer3":"Topcat","answer4":"Fleabag","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"John Logie Baird is credited with which invention?","correctAnswer":"TV","answer2":"Radio","answer3":"Telephone","answer4":"Gramaphone","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"What is the hottest planet in our solar system?","correctAnswer":"Venus","answer2":"Mercury","answer3":"Mars","answer4":"Earth","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"Tim Berners-Lee is known as the inventor of what?","correctAnswer":"World Wide Web","answer2":"Apple Computers","answer3":"Computer Mouse","answer4":"Email","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which plant gives absynthe its hallucinogenic properties?","correctAnswer":"wormwood","answer2":"holly","answer3":"mistletoe","answer4":"juniper","topic":"science","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which temperature has the same value in degrees in both centigrade and Fahrenheit?","correctAnswer":-40,"answer2":0,"answer3":37,"answer4":-273,"topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many moons does Venus have?","correctAnswer":0,"answer2":1,"answer3":2,"answer4":3,"topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What percentage of US dogs are overweight?","correctAnswer":"40%","answer2":"80%","answer3":"60%","answer4":"10%","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many feet in a fathom?","correctAnswer":6,"answer2":8,"answer3":12,"answer4":36,"topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"In computing how many bits make one byte?","correctAnswer":8,"answer2":16,"answer3":12,"answer4":4,"topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many arms does a squid have?","correctAnswer":10,"answer2":8,"answer3":6,"answer4":12,"topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many sides does a dodecagon have?","correctAnswer":12,"answer2":10,"answer3":20,"answer4":22,"topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What was the number of the last Apollo mission?","correctAnswer":17,"answer2":13,"answer3":29,"answer4":14,"topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many moons does Saturn have?","correctAnswer":18,"answer2":8,"answer3":28,"answer4":48,"topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"On average, how many hours a day does a Koala bear spend sleeping?","correctAnswer":22,"answer2":2,"answer3":12,"answer4":8,"topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many miles must one walk in order to burn off a pound of fat?","correctAnswer":34,"answer2":4,"answer3":14,"answer4":64,"topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"According to Guinness what is the record number of children borne by one woman?","correctAnswer":69,"answer2":26,"answer3":43,"answer4":88,"topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many nuclear power plants are there in the USA?","correctAnswer":109,"answer2":59,"answer3":209,"answer4":509,"topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many chemical elements are there?","correctAnswer":112,"answer2":212,"answer3":312,"answer4":412,"topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many litres are there in a barrel of oil?","correctAnswer":159,"answer2":59,"answer3":29,"answer4":189,"topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"The first robot was introduced in which year?","correctAnswer":1921,"answer2":1941,"answer3":1951,"answer4":1891,"topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"The Bikini was a concept by Louis Réard, but in which year?","correctAnswer":1946,"answer2":1966,"answer3":1926,"answer4":1906,"topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"The first working computer mouse was developed by Douglas Engelbart in which year?","correctAnswer":1963,"answer2":1973,"answer3":1983,"answer4":1993,"topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"The LCD or Liquid Crystal Display was first developed by James Fergason in which year?","correctAnswer":1971,"answer2":1981,"answer3":1961,"answer4":1951,"topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"The world's firsr pocket calculator was invented by the Sharp Corporation in which year?","correctAnswer":1971,"answer2":1981,"answer3":1991,"answer4":1961,"topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which year did Ernő Rubik invent the Rubik's cube?","correctAnswer":1974,"answer2":1964,"answer3":1984,"answer4":1954,"topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"The first Mobile phone was invented by Bell Labs in which year?","correctAnswer":1977,"answer2":1987,"answer3":1982,"answer4":1972,"topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"The Compact Disc was first developed by Philips Electronics and Sony Corp and released in which year?","correctAnswer":1980,"answer2":1985,"answer3":1990,"answer4":1975,"topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"DNA fingerprinting was first explained to the world by Alec Jeffreys in which year?","correctAnswer":1985,"answer2":1975,"answer3":1965,"answer4":1995,"topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which year was the satellite Galileo launched?","correctAnswer":1989,"answer2":1979,"answer3":1999,"answer4":1969,"topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which year did Tim Berners-Lee introduce the phrase World Wide Web?","correctAnswer":1990,"answer2":1985,"answer3":1995,"answer4":1980,"topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many muscles are there in an elephants trunk?","correctAnswer":40000.0,"answer2":4000.0,"answer3":400,"answer4":40,"topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many feet long was the largest Blue Whale ever seen?","correctAnswer":"110 ft","answer2":"55 ft","answer3":"210 ft","answer4":"550 ft","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What speed can a human reach in free fall?","correctAnswer":"155 miles per hr","answer2":"225 miles per hr","answer3":"55 miles per hour","answer4":"355 miles per hour","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"The first ballpoint pen was invented by Laszlo Biro in which decade?","correctAnswer":"1930s","answer2":"1950s","answer3":"1960s","answer4":"1910s","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"The world's first microwave oven was built and demonstrated by Percy Spencer in which decade?","correctAnswer":"1940s","answer2":"1960s","answer3":"1970s","answer4":"1980s","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which decade did the World Health Organisation declare Smallpox eradicated?","correctAnswer":"1970s","answer2":"1960s","answer3":"1980s","answer4":"1950s","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What generation is the so-called EDGE technology?","correctAnswer":"2.75G","answer2":"2.5G","answer3":"2G","answer4":"3G","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"On average, how long does a giraffe sleep each day?","correctAnswer":"20 min","answer2":"2 min","answer3":"2 hours","answer4":"20 hours","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"How much taller is the Eiffel tower in the summertime?","correctAnswer":"6 inches","answer2":"6 feet","answer3":"6 yards","answer4":"0 inches","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What is the sum of the internal angles in a hexagon?","correctAnswer":"720 degrees","answer2":"360 degrees","answer3":"1080 degrees","answer4":"540 degrees","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"For how long is a dog pregnant?","correctAnswer":"9 Weeks","answer2":"9 Days","answer3":"9 Months","answer4":"9 Fortnights","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What are Lanthanides?","correctAnswer":"A block of elements in the periodic table","answer2":"Mountains on Earth","answer3":"Mountains on the Moon","answer4":"Bacterium","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which continent did the ostrich originate?","correctAnswer":"Africa","answer2":"Australia","answer3":"North America","answer4":"Asia","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which of the following insects requires no sleep?","correctAnswer":"Ant","answer2":"Cockroach","answer3":"Termite","answer4":"Bee","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What part of the body does a turtle use to breathe?","correctAnswer":"Anus","answer2":"Belly","answer3":"Shell","answer4":"Mouth","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What can you see with Kirlian photography?","correctAnswer":"aura","answer2":"bones","answer3":"blood cells","answer4":"atoms","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"Animals of the Ursidae family are what?","correctAnswer":"Bears","answer2":"Dogs","answer3":"Apes","answer4":"Horses","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What colour skin does a polar bear have?","correctAnswer":"Black","answer2":"White","answer3":"Pink","answer4":"Grey","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What is an Ishihara test used for? ","correctAnswer":"Blindness","answer2":"Pregnancy","answer3":"Diabetes","answer4":"Deafness","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"Cats are born with which colour eyes?","correctAnswer":"Blue","answer2":"Grey","answer3":"Brown","answer4":"Red","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What colour of tongue does the chow breed of dog have?","correctAnswer":"Blue","answer2":"Red","answer3":"Pink","answer4":"Black","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What colour is lobster blood?","correctAnswer":"Blue","answer2":"Red","answer3":"Clear","answer4":"Yellow","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What colour is octopus blood?","correctAnswer":"blue","answer2":"red","answer3":"green","answer4":"yellow","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What are bactrians and dromedaries?","correctAnswer":"Camels","answer2":"Elephants","answer3":"Bears","answer4":"Sloths","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which element is present in all organic compounds?","correctAnswer":"Carbon","answer2":"Calcium","answer3":"Copper","answer4":"Californium","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What type of animal is considered good luck to have living at a theatre?","correctAnswer":"Cat","answer2":"Dog","answer3":"Bird","answer4":"Mouse","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"A blue Orpington is a breed of which animal?","correctAnswer":"Chicken","answer2":"Cat","answer3":"Cow","answer4":"Horse","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which of the following animals has the best memory?","correctAnswer":"Chimpanzee","answer2":"Elephant","answer3":"Donkey","answer4":"Rhino","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What did John Harrison invent in 1757?","correctAnswer":"chronometer","answer2":"parking meter","answer3":"taxi meter","answer4":"thermometer","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What was not the name of a US space mission?","correctAnswer":"Colombus","answer2":"Galileo","answer3":"Cassini","answer4":"Magellan","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which beetle loves potatoes?","correctAnswer":"Colorado","answer2":"Florida","answer3":"Utah","answer4":"Oregon","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What did Douglas Engelbart invent in 1963?","correctAnswer":"Computer Mouse","answer2":"Pocket Calculator","answer3":"Email","answer4":"Mobile Phone","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What makes up 99.9% of the universe?","correctAnswer":"dark energy","answer2":"H2O","answer3":"stars","answer4":"quarks","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"When cats have blue eyes they are also most likely what?","correctAnswer":"Deaf","answer2":"Female","answer3":"Male","answer4":"Blind","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"A wapiti is a what?","correctAnswer":"Deer","answer2":"Monkey","answer3":"Bat","answer4":"Rat","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What kind of animal is a Lurcher?","correctAnswer":"Dog","answer2":"Reptile","answer3":"Fish","answer4":"Bird","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"Cynophobia is the fear of what?","correctAnswer":"Dogs","answer2":"China","answer3":"The Dark","answer4":"Spiders","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which of the following insects can fly at a speed of around 60 mph?","correctAnswer":"Dragonfly","answer2":"Mosquito","answer3":"Hornet","answer4":"Bee","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which of the following mammals cannot jump?","correctAnswer":"Elephant","answer2":"Giraffe","answer3":"Hippo","answer4":"Rhino","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What was the name of the first digital computer?","correctAnswer":"ENIAC","answer2":"MANIAC","answer3":"PONTIAC","answer4":"NICKNACK","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"Where in your body would you find the rods and cones?","correctAnswer":"Eyes","answer2":"Ears","answer3":"Fingers","answer4":"Lungs","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which European country has the most nuclear power plants?","correctAnswer":"France","answer2":"Russia","answer3":"GB","answer4":"Germany","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which type of bomb was invented by Edward Teller and Stanislaw Ulam in 1952?","correctAnswer":"Fusion","answer2":"Fission","answer3":"Bouncing","answer4":"Napalm","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"Who said \"nature abhors a vacuum\"?","correctAnswer":"Galileo","answer2":"Einstein","answer3":"Aristotle","answer4":"Newton","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which European country has sent the most people into space?","correctAnswer":"Germany","answer2":"United Kingdom","answer3":"Italy","answer4":"Bulgaria","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"Where in Europe is the Barbary ape most likely found?","correctAnswer":"Gibralta","answer2":"Greece","answer3":"Bulgaria","answer4":"Portugal","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which of the following animals are not rodents?","correctAnswer":"Hedgehogs","answer2":"Rats","answer3":"Gophers","answer4":"Chipmunks","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What does a 'Hippophagic' eat?","correctAnswer":"horse meat","answer2":"dog meat","answer3":"cat meat","answer4":"whale meat","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"Ir is the chemical symbol for which element?","correctAnswer":"Iridium","answer2":"Iron","answer3":"Iodine","answer4":"Iritum","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What is a bird’s ‘gizzard’?","correctAnswer":"It’s second stomach","answer2":"It's beak","answer3":"It's tail feather","answer4":"It's distinctive colour","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What is the chemical symbol for Potassium?","correctAnswer":"K","answer2":"P","answer3":"Po","answer4":"Ka","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What are young squirrels called?","correctAnswer":"Kittens","answer2":"Pups","answer3":"Kids","answer4":"Ankle biters","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What are baby beavers called?","correctAnswer":"Kittens","answer2":"Pups","answer3":"Cubs","answer4":"Pests","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"Mg is the chemical symbol for which element?","correctAnswer":"Magnesium","answer2":"Manganese","answer3":"Molybdenum","answer4":"Tungsten","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"Mn is the chemical symbol for which element?","correctAnswer":"Manganese","answer2":"Magnesium","answer3":"Molybdenum","answer4":"Tungsten","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What is the scientific name for laughing gas?","correctAnswer":"Nitrous oxide","answer2":"Carbon dioxide","answer3":"Sulphur dioxide","answer4":"Nitrous dioxide","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What colour is an aircraft's black box?","correctAnswer":"Orange","answer2":"Red","answer3":"White","answer4":"Black","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"With which name do we refer to a female cat?","correctAnswer":"Queen","answer2":"Doe","answer3":"Bitch","answer4":"Kitty","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What does a Becquerel unit measure?","correctAnswer":"Radioactivity","answer2":"Energy","answer3":"Pressure","answer4":"Frequency","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which of the following animals can last the longest without water?","correctAnswer":"Rat","answer2":"Camel","answer3":"Human","answer4":"Goat","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"The common cold is what kind of virus?","correctAnswer":"Rhino","answer2":"Leo","answer3":"Avian","answer4":"Pisces","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What is the chemical symbol for Antimony?","correctAnswer":"Sb","answer2":"Ti","answer3":"T","answer4":"Sn","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which of the following is a theory in physics?","correctAnswer":"Schrodinger's Cat","answer2":"Schrodinger's Rat","answer3":"Schrodinger's Hat","answer4":"Schrodinger's Bat","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What was not the name of a US space mission?","correctAnswer":"Scout","answer2":"Mariner","answer3":"Ranger","answer4":"Pioneer","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What did Otto Frederick Rohwedder invent in 1928 that changed the world forever?","correctAnswer":"Sliced bread","answer2":"RADAR","answer3":"The refrigerator","answer4":"The television","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What does an OLF unit measure?","correctAnswer":"smell","answer2":"taste","answer3":"light ","answer4":"heat","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What is the chemical symbol for Tin?","correctAnswer":"Sn","answer2":"Ti","answer3":"T","answer4":"Sb","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"On the Mohs scale the hardest substance is diamond - what's the softest?","correctAnswer":"Talcum Powder","answer2":"Wheat Flour","answer3":"Sugar","answer4":"Skin dust","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What is the chemical symbol for Titanium?","correctAnswer":"Ti","answer2":"Sn","answer3":"T","answer4":"Sb","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"Ti is the chemical symbol for which element?","correctAnswer":"Titanium","answer2":"Tin","answer3":"Thorium","answer4":"Thulium","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which part of the human body contains the most gold?","correctAnswer":"Toenails","answer2":"Fingernails","answer3":"Hair","answer4":"Skin","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"W is the chemical symbol for which element?","correctAnswer":"Tungsten","answer2":"Magnesium","answer3":"Molybdenum","answer4":"Manganese","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which planet in the Solar System is closest in size to Earth? ","correctAnswer":"Venus","answer2":"Mercury","answer3":"Mars","answer4":"Uranus","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What was the name of Jurij Gagarin's space capsule?","correctAnswer":"Vostok I","answer2":"MIR","answer3":"Sojus II","answer4":"Sputnik I","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"Ergasiophobia is the fear of what?","correctAnswer":"Work","answer2":"Flatulence","answer3":"Odour","answer4":"Belching","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which plant gives absinthe its hallucinogenic properties?","correctAnswer":"wormwood","answer2":"mandrake","answer3":"agara","answer4":"belladonna","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"What kind of star is our sun?","correctAnswer":"Yellow Dwarf","answer2":"Red Giant","answer3":"Brown Dwarf","answer4":"White Dwarf","topic":"science","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many stomachs does a moth have?","correctAnswer":0,"answer2":1,"answer3":32,"answer4":102,"topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which percentage of the worlds population has an I.Q. of 120 or more ?","correctAnswer":"12.50%","answer2":"1.20%","answer3":"25.50%","answer4":"48.50%","topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"How many hearts does an earthworm have?","correctAnswer":5,"answer2":0,"answer3":1,"answer4":250,"topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"How many 'arms' does a snowflake have?","correctAnswer":6,"answer2":5,"answer3":8,"answer4":9,"topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"How many minutes does it take rays from the sun to reach the earth","correctAnswer":8,"answer2":6,"answer3":10,"answer4":12,"topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"How many people have walked on the moon? ","correctAnswer":12,"answer2":9,"answer3":6,"answer4":3,"topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"How many inches to a cubit?","correctAnswer":18,"answer2":16,"answer3":12,"answer4":21,"topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"How many brains does a leech have?","correctAnswer":32,"answer2":0,"answer3":1,"answer4":102,"topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"How many gallons of water can a camel drink in 10 minutes?","correctAnswer":35,"answer2":5,"answer3":15,"answer4":25,"topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"How many muscles does it take to move your hand?","correctAnswer":35,"answer2":5,"answer3":15,"answer4":65,"topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"How many cubic feet are there in three cubic yards?","correctAnswer":81,"answer2":9,"answer3":144,"answer4":27,"topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"How many years is 1,000,000 hours?","correctAnswer":114,"answer2":111,"answer3":211,"answer4":214,"topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"How many sq metres was ENIAC, the worlds first electronic computer?","correctAnswer":170,"answer2":70,"answer3":7,"answer4":770,"topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which year was the ball point pen introduced?","correctAnswer":1938,"answer2":1958,"answer3":1888,"answer4":1908,"topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"Ray Tomlinson sent the world's first email in which year?","correctAnswer":1971,"answer2":1981,"answer3":1991,"answer4":2001,"topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which year was the first black tulip cultivated?","correctAnswer":1986,"answer2":1896,"answer3":2006,"answer4":1926,"topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"How many hairs does the average human head have?","correctAnswer":100000.0,"answer2":1000000.0,"answer3":10000.0,"answer4":1000.0,"topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"Roughly how many glasses of milk can one cow produce in one year?","correctAnswer":120000.0,"answer2":520000.0,"answer3":20000.0,"answer4":720000.0,"topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"What was the highest ever recorded temperature in the Libyan desert?","correctAnswer":"136 degrees Fahrenheit","answer2":"180 degrees Fahrenheit","answer3":"156 degrees Fahrenheit","answer4":"236 degrees Fahrenheit","topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"What is the speed of light?","correctAnswer":"186,272 miles per second","answer2":"84,272 miles per second","answer3":"286,272 miles per second","answer4":"1,188 ,272 miles per second","topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"In 1776 what was the average height of an Englishman?","correctAnswer":"5 ft 7 inches","answer2":"5 ft 4 inches","answer3":"6 foot","answer4":"5 ft 1 inch","topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"How long does the light from the sun take to reach the earth?","correctAnswer":"8.5 min","answer2":"8.5 hours","answer3":"8.5 sec","answer4":"8.5 days","topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"Bamboo plants can grow how many cm per day?","correctAnswer":"90cm","answer2":"10cm","answer3":"30cm","answer4":"170cm","topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"What is the most common blood group in Europe?","correctAnswer":"A +","answer2":"A -","answer3":"B +","answer4":"O -","topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"What does a nidoligist study?","correctAnswer":"Bird Nests","answer2":"Waves","answer3":"Clouds","answer4":"Caves","topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which of these elements is the heaviest?","correctAnswer":"Caesium","answer2":"Rubidium","answer3":"Potassium","answer4":"Sodium","topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"How many earths would fit inside the sun?","correctAnswer":"circa 1,000,000","answer2":"circa 1,000","answer3":"circa 10,000","answer4":"circa 100,000","topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"Hypermetropic people are what?","correctAnswer":"far sighted","answer2":"obese","answer3":"underfed","answer4":"moody","topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"Fredrick Sanger invented which life saver?","correctAnswer":"Insulin","answer2":"Safety Pin","answer3":"Inflatable Life Raft","answer4":"Aspirin","topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which of the following is a bird AND a fruit?","correctAnswer":"Kiwi","answer2":"Juju","answer3":"Mango","answer4":"Pear","topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which planet has the tallest mountain?","correctAnswer":"Mars","answer2":"Earth","answer3":"Jupiter","answer4":"Venus","topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"What does the medical term dolent mean?","correctAnswer":"pain","answer2":"fever","answer3":"numb","answer4":"internal","topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which of these is a name of a fish?","correctAnswer":"Parr","answer2":"Aragon","answer3":"Boleyn","answer4":"Seymour","topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"What is the only food a cockroach wont eat?","correctAnswer":"pickle","answer2":"snail","answer3":"marshmellow","answer4":"porridge","topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"What won't a cockroach eat?","correctAnswer":"pickles","answer2":"porridge","answer3":"curry","answer4":"marmite","topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which planet has the most eccentric orbit?","correctAnswer":"Pluto","answer2":"Mercury","answer3":"Earth","answer4":"Venus","topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"What is a Flemish Giant?","correctAnswer":"Rabbit","answer2":"Star","answer3":"Sprout","answer4":"Mountain","topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"A 'bind' is a group of what?","correctAnswer":"salmon","answer2":"crows","answer3":"zebras","answer4":"cobras","topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which planet has the most moons?","correctAnswer":"Saturn","answer2":"Jupiter","answer3":"Neptune","answer4":"Uranus","topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which bird has a record 25,000 feathers?","correctAnswer":"Swan","answer2":"Goose","answer3":"Albatross","answer4":"Stork","topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"Somatology is the study of what?","correctAnswer":"The Body","answer2":"The Cosmos","answer3":"Insects","answer4":"Somalia","topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"Who invented the sub-machine gun in 1920?","correctAnswer":"Thompson","answer2":"Gattling","answer3":"Colt","answer4":"Winchester","topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"Brontophobia is the fear of what?","correctAnswer":"Thunder","answer2":"Skyscrapers","answer3":"Elephants","answer4":"The Dark","topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which VW auto was not named after a wind?","correctAnswer":"Touran","answer2":"Passat","answer3":"Scirocco","answer4":"Bora","topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"A Blue Whale has a heart roughly the size of a what?","correctAnswer":"VW Beetle","answer2":"Basketball","answer3":"Grapefruit","answer4":"Peanut","topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"Anemophobia is the fear of what?","correctAnswer":"Wind","answer2":"Spiders","answer3":"The Dark","answer4":"Fire","topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"What is the more usual name for Roentgen Rays?","correctAnswer":"X Rays","answer2":"Gamma Rays","answer3":"Ultra Violet Rays","answer4":"Magnetic Resonance","topic":"science","difficulty":3},{"question":"How many holes are there on a ten pin bowling ball?","correctAnswer":3,"answer2":4,"answer3":2,"answer4":5,"topic":"sport","difficulty":1},{"question":"How many rings on the Olympic flag?","correctAnswer":5,"answer2":4,"answer3":6,"answer4":7,"topic":"sport","difficulty":1},{"question":"How many Olympic gold medals did mark Spitz win in Munich in 1972?","correctAnswer":7,"answer2":8,"answer3":6,"answer4":5,"topic":"sport","difficulty":1},{"question":"How many lanes does an Olympic swimming pool have?","correctAnswer":8,"answer2":6,"answer3":10,"answer4":12,"topic":"sport","difficulty":1},{"question":"How many rounds are there in a professional boxing title contest?","correctAnswer":12,"answer2":10,"answer3":20,"answer4":8,"topic":"sport","difficulty":1},{"question":"In badminton, how many points win a single game?","correctAnswer":15,"answer2":20,"answer3":10,"answer4":19,"topic":"sport","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which 1982 World Cup team featured the talents of Zico, Socrates and Falcao?","correctAnswer":"Brazil","answer2":"Italy","answer3":"Spain","answer4":"Argentina","topic":"sport","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which swimming stroke was not introduced to the Olympics until 1956?","correctAnswer":"Butterfly","answer2":"Freestyle","answer3":"Breaststroke","answer4":"Doggy Style","topic":"sport","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which country has Zinedine Zidane played for?","correctAnswer":"France","answer2":"Italy","answer3":"Spain","answer4":"Brazil","topic":"sport","difficulty":1},{"question":"In tennis, what name is given to winning the four major tournaments in a season?","correctAnswer":"Grand Slam","answer2":"Outright","answer3":"World Champion","answer4":"Major Slam","topic":"sport","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which of these is another name for a golf course?","correctAnswer":"Links","answer2":"Pitch","answer3":"Steps","answer4":"Suite","topic":"sport","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which tennis players nickname was 'The Rocket'?","correctAnswer":"Rod Laver","answer2":"Fred Perry","answer3":"Pete Sampras","answer4":"John Newcombe","topic":"sport","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which sport is played in Roland Garros?","correctAnswer":"tennis","answer2":"rugby","answer3":"football","answer4":"polo","topic":"sport","difficulty":1},{"question":"Which superstar was named 'The Great One'?","correctAnswer":"Wayne Gretsky","answer2":"Rod Laver","answer3":"Eddie Edwards","answer4":"Dixie Dean","topic":"sport","difficulty":1},{"question":"What type of sportsman was the toy Stretch Armstrong dressed as?","correctAnswer":"Wrestler","answer2":"Boxer","answer3":"Archer","answer4":"Cricketer","topic":"sport","difficulty":1},{"question":"How many Gold Medals did Jesse Owens win in the 1936 Berlin Olympics? ","correctAnswer":4,"answer2":3,"answer3":5,"answer4":6,"topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many hulls are there on a Catamaran?","correctAnswer":4,"answer2":3,"answer3":2,"answer4":1,"topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many balls are used in a game of croquet?","correctAnswer":4,"answer2":2,"answer3":8,"answer4":1,"topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many players are there in a polo team?","correctAnswer":4,"answer2":2,"answer3":8,"answer4":16,"topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many times did cyclist Miguel Indurain win the Tour de France in the 1990s?","correctAnswer":5,"answer2":9,"answer3":2,"answer4":"None","topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many games make up a match in squash?","correctAnswer":5,"answer2":10,"answer3":12,"answer4":8,"topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many players of an ice hockey team can be on the ice at the same time?","correctAnswer":6,"answer2":5,"answer3":7,"answer4":8,"topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many disciplines make up the men’s gymnastics competition at the Olympics?","correctAnswer":6,"answer2":8,"answer3":10,"answer4":4,"topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"What is the minimum number of points needed to win a game of squash?","correctAnswer":9,"answer2":10,"answer3":20,"answer4":15,"topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many players in a baseball team?","correctAnswer":9,"answer2":11,"answer3":15,"answer4":7,"topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"What number shirt did Pele usually wear when playing for Brazil?","correctAnswer":10,"answer2":9,"answer3":8,"answer4":1,"topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many players are there in a Hockey team?","correctAnswer":11,"answer2":15,"answer3":9,"answer4":10,"topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"In American Football, how many players from one team are allowed on the grid at any one time?","correctAnswer":11,"answer2":15,"answer3":10,"answer4":12,"topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"How many minutes of play are there in an American football match?","correctAnswer":60,"answer2":90,"answer3":120,"answer4":150,"topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"In which year did tennis legend 'Rocket' Rod Laver win his last Grand Slam?","correctAnswer":1969,"answer2":1977,"answer3":1981,"answer4":1958,"topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which city hosted the 1992 summer Olympic games?","correctAnswer":"Barcelona","answer2":"Atlanta","answer3":"Moscow","answer4":"Seoul","topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"What did the dog named Pickles find?","correctAnswer":"Coupe Jules Rimet","answer2":"Davis Cup","answer3":"Federation Cup","answer4":"F.A. Cup","topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"\"The ugliest salad bowl in the world\" is the nickname for which trophy?","correctAnswer":"Davis Cup","answer2":"F.A. Cup","answer3":"Ryder Cup","answer4":"Football World Cup","topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"Wayne Gretzky was a superstar in which sport?","correctAnswer":"ice hochey","answer2":"golf","answer3":"tennis","answer4":"boxing","topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which tennis player has not lost four Wimbledon singles finals?","correctAnswer":"Ivan Lendl","answer2":"Jimmy Connors","answer3":"Boris Becker","answer4":"Ken Rosewall","topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"Who was the only tennis player to have won the US OPEN on three different surfaces?","correctAnswer":"Jimmy Conners ","answer2":"Roger Federer ","answer3":"Big Bill Tilden     ","answer4":"Andre Agassi","topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"Mika Hakkinen was Formula 1 champion in 1998 and 1999 in which car?","correctAnswer":"McLaren-Mercedes","answer2":"Ferrari","answer3":"Renault","answer4":"Benetton Ford","topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"'El tri' is the nickname for which national football team? ","correctAnswer":"Mexico","answer2":"Brazil","answer3":"Spain","answer4":"Switzerland","topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which summer Olympic Games were boycotted by most African countries?","correctAnswer":"Montreal 76","answer2":"Moscow 80","answer3":"Munich 72","answer4":"USA 84","topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"Jacky Ickx was a superstar in which sport?","correctAnswer":"motor racing","answer2":"cycling","answer3":"soccer","answer4":"tennis","topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"Every player in the Bulgarian national team at the 1994 Football World Cup had a name ending in which letters?","correctAnswer":"ov","answer2":"ki","answer3":"us","answer4":"an","topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which country has won a record four World Championships in mens field hockey?","correctAnswer":"Pakistan","answer2":"Germany","answer3":"Holland","answer4":"Ireland","topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"80% of all the footballs in the world are made in which country?","correctAnswer":"Pakistan","answer2":"USA","answer3":"Mexico","answer4":"Australia","topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"Who was the last man to win the Grand Slam in tennis?","correctAnswer":"Rod Laver","answer2":"Bjorn Borg","answer3":"Roger Federer","answer4":"Ivan Lendl","topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which stadium is named after a WW I flying ace?","correctAnswer":"Roland Garros","answer2":"Giuseppe Meazza","answer3":"Fratton Park","answer4":"Bernabeu","topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which city saw Steffi Graf win Olympic gold?","correctAnswer":"Seoul","answer2":"Barcelona","answer3":"Los Angeles","answer4":"Moscow","topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"'Wedel' is a term in which sport?","correctAnswer":"Skiing","answer2":"Darts","answer3":"Chess","answer4":"Formula One","topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"In golf what name is given to the No 3 wood?","correctAnswer":"Spoon","answer2":"Knife","answer3":"Fork","answer4":"Ladel","topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which woman thrashed her opponent 6-0 6-0 in the 1988 French Open final?","correctAnswer":"Stefi Graf","answer2":"Venus Williams","answer3":"Billy Jean King","answer4":"Virginia Wade","topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"What weighs 4lb 6oz at the Olympics?","correctAnswer":"The Discuss","answer2":"The Javelin","answer3":"The Olympic Torch","answer4":"The Medals (Gold, Silver, Bronze)","topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"Which football world cup had the highest average attendance figures?","correctAnswer":"USA 94","answer2":"Brazil 50","answer3":"England 66","answer4":"Italy 90","topic":"sport","difficulty":2},{"question":"If a golf hole is 130 yards long, what would its par be?","correctAnswer":3,"answer2":2,"answer3":4,"answer4":5,"topic":"sport","difficulty":3},{"question":"How many laps are completed towin a speedway race?","correctAnswer":4,"answer2":5,"answer3":6,"answer4":10,"topic":"sport","difficulty":3},{"question":"How many baseball gloves can be made with the leather from one cow?","correctAnswer":5,"answer2":1,"answer3":25,"answer4":55,"topic":"sport","difficulty":3},{"question":"How old was Boris Becker when he won his first Wimbledon singles title?","correctAnswer":17,"answer2":16,"answer3":15,"answer4":18,"topic":"sport","difficulty":3},{"question":"How many Wimbledon titles did Billie Jean King win?","correctAnswer":20,"answer2":30,"answer3":10,"answer4":5,"topic":"sport","difficulty":3},{"question":"How many laps are run in a 10000-metre track race?","correctAnswer":25,"answer2":20,"answer3":30,"answer4":35,"topic":"sport","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which year were the summer olympic games in Berlin? ","correctAnswer":1936,"answer2":1932,"answer3":1942,"answer4":1948,"topic":"sport","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which year were the summer olympic games in Montreal? ","correctAnswer":1976,"answer2":1980,"answer3":1974,"answer4":1978,"topic":"sport","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which year were the summer olympic games in Moscow?","correctAnswer":1980,"answer2":1982,"answer3":1978,"answer4":1976,"topic":"sport","difficulty":3},{"question":"Countries from which continent boycotted the 1976 summer olympics in Montreal?","correctAnswer":"Africa","answer2":"Europe","answer3":"Asia","answer4":"South  America","topic":"sport","difficulty":3},{"question":"Who was the first black woman to win both the US Open and Wimbledon?","correctAnswer":"Althea Gibson","answer2":"Venus Williams","answer3":"Shirley Fry","answer4":"Serena Williams","topic":"sport","difficulty":3},{"question":"Who is not an accomplished fencer?","correctAnswer":"Arnold Schwarzenegger","answer2":"Gene Wilder","answer3":"Elijah Wood","answer4":"Antonio Banderas","topic":"sport","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which sport do the Minnesota Twins play?","correctAnswer":"Baseball","answer2":"Ice Hiockey","answer3":"Basketball","answer4":"Football","topic":"sport","difficulty":3},{"question":"Who was the first american to win the mens singles title at Wimbledon?","correctAnswer":"Big Bill Tilden","answer2":"Donald Budge","answer3":"Jack Kramer","answer4":"Bobby Riggs","topic":"sport","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which NHL superstar had the nickname 'The Golden Jet'?","correctAnswer":"Bobby Hull","answer2":"Bobby Orr","answer3":"Gordie Howe","answer4":"Stan Mikita","topic":"sport","difficulty":3},{"question":"Figure skating champion Elvis Stojko was from which country?","correctAnswer":"Canada","answer2":"Russia","answer3":"USA","answer4":"Bulgaria","topic":"sport","difficulty":3},{"question":"Who was the captain of Brazil when they won the 1970 football world cup?","correctAnswer":"Carlos Alberto","answer2":"Pele","answer3":"Romario","answer4":"Socrates","topic":"sport","difficulty":3},{"question":"Eddy Merckx was a superstar in which sport?","correctAnswer":"cycling","answer2":"soccer","answer3":"tennis","answer4":"baseball","topic":"sport","difficulty":3},{"question":"Who has a black belt in judo?","correctAnswer":"David Lee Roth","answer2":"Bill Gates","answer3":"David Beckham","answer4":"Prince Charles","topic":"sport","difficulty":3},{"question":"Nine time Olympic gold medal winner Paavo Nurmi was from which country?","correctAnswer":"Finland","answer2":"Russia","answer3":"India","answer4":"Hungary","topic":"sport","difficulty":3},{"question":"Juan Manuel Fangio was a superstar in which sport in the 1950s?","correctAnswer":"formula one","answer2":"tennis","answer3":"baseball","answer4":"soccer","topic":"sport","difficulty":3},{"question":"In which sport does one compete for the Stanley Cup?","correctAnswer":"ice hockey","answer2":"polo","answer3":"golf","answer4":"squash","topic":"sport","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which poem greets contestants to centre court Wimbledon?","correctAnswer":"If","answer2":"All the worlds a stage","answer3":"The road not taken","answer4":"A dream within a dream","topic":"sport","difficulty":3},{"question":"Who does not have a black belt in karate?","correctAnswer":"Jennifer Lopez","answer2":"Sharon Stone","answer3":"Chuck Norris","answer4":"Guy Ritchie","topic":"sport","difficulty":3},{"question":"What was the name of the mascot bear at the 1980 summer Olympic games in Moscow?","correctAnswer":"Mischa","answer2":"Olga","answer3":"Igor","answer4":"Nikita","topic":"sport","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which NHL hockey team has won the most Stanley Cups?","correctAnswer":"Montreal Canadiens","answer2":"Toronto Maple Leafs","answer3":"Boston Bruins","answer4":"New York Rangers","topic":"sport","difficulty":3},{"question":"At which Formula One circuit would one find the 'Lesmo Bend'?","correctAnswer":"Monza","answer2":"Circuit Gilles Villeneuve","answer3":"Hockenheimring","answer4":"Silverstone","topic":"sport","difficulty":3},{"question":"Speed skating originated in which country?","correctAnswer":"Netherlands","answer2":"Canada","answer3":"Norway","answer4":"Russia","topic":"sport","difficulty":3},{"question":"Which professional sport awards the Lady Byng Memorial Trophy each year for the 'Most Gentlemanly Player'?","correctAnswer":"NHL","answer2":"NFL","answer3":"PGA","answer4":"NBA","topic":"sport","difficulty":3},{"question":"'Nati' is the nickname for which countrys football team?","correctAnswer":"Switzerland","answer2":"South Korea","answer3":"Holland","answer4":"Mexico","topic":"sport","difficulty":3},{"question":"Gossima was the original name for which sport?","correctAnswer":"Table Tennis","answer2":"Lawn Tennis","answer3":"Badminton","answer4":"Snooker","topic":"sport","difficulty":3},{"question":"Lew Hoad was a superstar in which sport in the 1950s?","correctAnswer":"tennis","answer2":"ice hockey","answer3":"baseball","answer4":"soccer","topic":"sport","difficulty":3},{"question":"A 'Miller' is a move in which sport?","correctAnswer":"Trampolining","answer2":"Diving","answer3":"Chess","answer4":"Ice Hockey","topic":"sport","difficulty":3}]